<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The duty and office of high-constables of hundreds, petty-constables, tythingmen, and such inferior ministers of the peace with the several duties and offices of churchwardens, overseers, and collectors for the poor, of surveyors for amending the higheways, and distributors of the provision for the destruction of noysom fowl and vermin / first collected by William Lambard, in the reign of Q. Elizabeth ; and now enlarged with many useful additions according to the succeeding statutes by R. Turner ...</title>
            <author>Lambarde, William, 1536-1601.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1671</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 191 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 79 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A48475</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L215A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R41023</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">19576793</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 19576793</idno>
            <idno type="VID">109137</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A48475)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 109137)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1691:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The duty and office of high-constables of hundreds, petty-constables, tythingmen, and such inferior ministers of the peace with the several duties and offices of churchwardens, overseers, and collectors for the poor, of surveyors for amending the higheways, and distributors of the provision for the destruction of noysom fowl and vermin / first collected by William Lambard, in the reign of Q. Elizabeth ; and now enlarged with many useful additions according to the succeeding statutes by R. Turner ...</title>
                  <author>Lambarde, William, 1536-1601.</author>
                  <author>Turner, R.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[12], 144 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Joh. Streater, Hen. Twyford, and Eliz. Flesher, the assigns of R. Atkins and E. Atkins ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1671.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"Cum gratia &amp; privilegio Regiæ Majestatis."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the University of Illinois (Urbana-Champaign Campus). Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Constables --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-02</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-02</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:109137:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:109137:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THE <hi>Duty</hi> and <hi>Office</hi> OF HIGH-CONSTABLES OF HUNDREDS, Petty-Conſtables, Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, and ſuch inferiour Miniſters of the Peace.</p>
            <p>WITH The ſeveral Duties and Offices of Churchwardens, Overſeers and Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectors for the Poor, of Surveyors for amending the Highwayes, and Diſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>butors of the proviſion for the Deſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction of noyſom Fowl and Vermin.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Firſt collected by</hi> William Lambard, <hi>in the reign of Queen</hi> Elizabeth; AND Now Enlarged with many uſeful Additions, according to the ſucceeding <hi>Statutes:</hi>
            </p>
            <p>By <hi>R. TURNER,</hi> Gent.</p>
            <p>LONDON: Printed by <hi>Ioh. Streater, Hen. Twyford,</hi> and <hi>Eliz. Fleſher,</hi> the Aſſigns of <hi>R. Atkins</hi> and <hi>E. Atkins</hi> Eſquires. 1671.</p>
            <p>Cum gratia &amp; privilegio Regiae Majeſtatis.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:109137:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:109137:2"/>
            <head>To the READERS.</head>
            <p>THe foundation of this little Structure was firſt laid by Mr. <hi>Lambard</hi> a long while ſince, in the Year <hi>1579.</hi> and first made publick in <hi>1581.</hi> and afterwards reviſed, and the ſecond Edition publiſhed in the year <hi>1587.</hi> but in ſo long time ſince the ſucceeding Age growing worſe and worſe, <hi>ut Creſcit in orbe dolus,</hi> our Law-makers have been forced to make Additional Laws for pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vention
<pb facs="tcp:109137:3"/>of Offences and puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Offendors; ſo that the Duties of theſe inferiour Officers of the Peace have ſtill increa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed as ſeveral Statutes dayly enacted do impoſe new Duties upon them: So that I have re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſed this Treatiſe, with ſuch neceſſary additions and enlarge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, as any ways may concern the Offices of <hi>Conſtables, Head<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boroughs,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Churchwardens, Overſeers</hi> of the Poor, <hi>Survey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ors</hi> of Highwayes and Bridges; or as they are enjoyn'd by any Laws ſince Mr. <hi>Lambard,</hi> to ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve &amp; perform in their ſeveral offices; and indeed, this ſmall Tract will be as uſeful to every perſon, whether Officer or not Officer,
<pb facs="tcp:109137:3"/>as a pocket-Almanack; to him that is in office, it is a Pilot to ſteer him in his right courſe, whereby he may avoid thoſe Rocks and Sands of Over-doing or <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nder-doing; ſome through neglect in not performing their duties are culpable by the ſupe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riour Magistrate, and others either ignorantly or wilfully run<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning beyond their Authority, are daſhed against the Rock of the Law. Thoſe that are in like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lyhood to bear any of theſe Offices, may by studying this Book be perfectly inſtructed in the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formance of their Duty when they come to it: And ſuch as are not likely to ſerve any Office, may herein learn to eſcape pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment
<pb facs="tcp:109137:4"/>by fearing to offend. I have ſet down the <hi>High-Conſtables</hi> Oath at large, which partly comprehends the whole duty of his Office; and ſuch Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticles as he is to preſent to the Justices of peace at their Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions and monthly Meetings in their Diviſions; and likewiſe that Statute which institutes the office of the Diſtributors of the proviſion for the Deſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of noyſom Fowl and Vermin; that is, what Reward ſhall be given to thoſe that deſtroy them; which ſome vulgarly and erro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neouſly talk of, others have af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmed there is no ſuch Law; but they will hereby be convin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced of the truth, and inſtructed
<pb facs="tcp:109137:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>in the ſubſtance: So that I hope this will prove to your acce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ptance, which is the deſire of</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>R. T.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="table_of_contents">
            <pb facs="tcp:109137:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:109137:5"/>
            <head>THE TABLE</head>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. I.</label>
               <item>
                  <list>
                     <item>THE original Office and Juriſdiction of High-Conſtables, Petty-Conſtables, Headboroughs, Borſholders and Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, <hi>Pag. 1.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Chap. idem.</hi> The form of the High-Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables Oath, <hi>Pag. 5.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Idem.</hi> The Oath of a Petty-Conſtable or Tythingman. <hi>Pag. 8.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. II.</label>
               <item>The duty of Conſtables and Headboroughs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in executing Warrants directed to them from the Juſtices of Peace. <hi>Pag. 14.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. III.</label>
               <item>Articles which the High-Constables are to return to the Juſtices at their Seſſions or monethly Meetings, <hi>&amp;c. Pag. 19.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <pb facs="tcp:109137:6"/>
               <label>CHAP. IV.</label>
               <item>The duty of Conſtables, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> touching Watch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, Warding, Vagabonds, Hue and Cry, carrying Priſoners to the Gaol, Servants and Labourers, <hi>Pag. 22.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. V.</label>
               <item>
                  <list>
                     <item>The form of a Teſtimonial for conveying a Rogue or Vagabond, <hi>Pag. 26.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Idem.</hi> A Teſtimonial for a Servant. <hi>Pag. 38.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. VI.</label>
               <item>The duty of Conſtables about Affrayes, Riots, Routs, Armes, Militia, Eſcapes, Forci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Entries, the Peace, Hedge-breakers, Setting-dogs. <hi>Pag. 40.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. VII.</label>
               <item>The Constables office touching Clothiers, Maultſters, Alehouſes, Drunkenneſs, Weights and Meaſures, Purveyances, Highwayes. <hi>Pag. 56.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. VIII.</label>
               <item>The Conſtables office about forein Bone<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laces, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Chimney-money, Cuſtomes, Exciſe, Fiſh. <hi>Pag. 71.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. IX.</label>
               <item>Concerning diſturbing of Miniſters, Swear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, Recuſants, Conventicles. <hi>Pag. 77.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <pb facs="tcp:109137:6"/>
               <label>CHAP. X.</label>
               <item>
                  <list>
                     <item>The Churchwardens office, <hi>Pag. 86.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Idem.</hi> The Subſcription of the Veſtry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, <hi>Pag. 91.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Idem.</hi> The form of the Articles given to the Churchwardens to make their Preſentments upon. <hi>Pag. 101.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. XI.</label>
               <item>
                  <list>
                     <item>The office of the Overſeers of the Poor, <hi>Pag. 110.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Idem.</hi> The form of an Indenture for a poor Child put out by the Pariſh. <hi>Pag. 117.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. XII.</label>
               <item>
                  <list>
                     <item>The office of the Surveyors of the Highwayes and Bridges, <hi>Pag. 122.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Idem.</hi> Statutes for repairing particular Highwayes, <hi>Pag. 134.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Idem.</hi> Statutes for particular Bridges. <hi>Pag. 135.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <label>CHAP. XIII.</label>
               <item>The office of the Diſtributors of the proviſion for the Deſtruction of noyſom Fowl and Vermin. <hi>Pag. 141.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:109137:7"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:109137:7"/>
            <head>THE DUTY OF CONSTABLES, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <div n="1" type="chapter">
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. I.</hi> Of the Original, Office, and Juriſdiction of High-Conſtables, Petty-Conſtables, Headboroughs, Borſholders, and Tythingmen.</head>
               <p>THE <hi>Saxon</hi> Chriſtian King <hi>Alfred,</hi> King of <hi>England,</hi> for the more peaceable Government and eaſe of his Subjects, divided this whole Realm of <hi>England</hi> firſt into Shires; then cauſed thoſe Shires to be ſubdivided into Hundreds, Rapes, Ridings, Wapentakes; and divided theſe alſo into Tythings, Leets
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:109137:8"/>or Boroughs, and in all theſe Diviſions were appointed Officers for the better preſerva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Peace, ſuch are High-Conſtables, Petty-Conſtables, Headboroughs, Borſhold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers and Tythingmen; the office of all theſe latter is one and the ſame, only different in Title, according to the cuſtome of the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey; in <hi>Middleſex,</hi> beſides the High-Conſtables of the Hundreds, they have Petty-Conſtables and Headboroughs in the reſpective Pariſhes, and they are in num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber more or leſs, according to the greatneſs or ſmalneſs of the Pariſh; in <hi>Kent</hi> theſe petty Officers of the Pariſhes are called Borſhold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers; but in <hi>Hampſhire</hi> and all the Weſtern parts Tythingmen, and their diviſions of Pariſhes Tythings; in <hi>Suſſex</hi> the Hundreds are called Rapes; and in the North, Ridings and Wapentakes.</p>
               <p>There was antiently in <hi>England</hi> a great Officer called the High Conſtable of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> and he kept an Office (which is ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed to come hither with <hi>William</hi> the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queror out of <hi>Normandy</hi>) or Court, called the Conſtables Court, or the Court of the High-Conſtable, wherein he had authority to hear and determine Contracts touching deeds of Armes out of the Realm, and to determine all things concerning War within
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:109137:8"/>the Realm; as Combats, Blazon, Armo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> but not to deal with Battel in ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peals, that belonging to the Common Law of the Land.</p>
               <p>Amongſt the reſt of the <hi>Conquerours</hi> Laws this is one, That if a <hi>French-man</hi> do appeal an <hi>Engliſh-man</hi> of Perjury or Murder, the <hi>French-man</hi> may defend himſelf by <hi>Battail,</hi> which in Engliſh was then called <hi>Earnest,</hi> which word we yet retain; and the Officer to ſee this performed was the High-Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable: but this Officer, Court and practice is long ſince diſſolved.</p>
               <p>The Etymologie of this word <hi>Conſtable</hi> proceeds from the old word <hi>Conning</hi> or <hi>Cyng,</hi> and <hi>Staple</hi> or <hi>Stable;</hi> the word <hi>Conning</hi> or <hi>Cyng,</hi> ſignifies a King, and <hi>Stable,</hi> a Stay or Prop; which is as much as to ſay, the <hi>ſtay</hi> or <hi>prop</hi> of the <hi>King;</hi> that great Officer the <hi>Conſtable</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving that Title given by reaſon of the great Authority that he had, was a principal Prop of Stay unto the Kings government; from whence is this Title and Office of this Lower Conſtableſhip derived and continued, (though with leſſer Authority, unto this hour) and is a branch of that Original.</p>
               <p>By the Statute of <hi>Wincheſter,</hi> made in the time of King <hi>Edward</hi> the Firſt, theſe Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:109137:9"/>of Hundreds were appointed to keep Watching and Warding, for the better keeping of the Peace, and prevention of Thieveries and Robberies, and apprehen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions of Felons and Rogues, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and that the High-Conſtables in every Hundred and Franchiſe, ſhould take the view of Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mour, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Hereby it appears, that the name of a <hi>Conſtable</hi> in an Hundred or Franchiſe, is an Officer to aſſiſt and ſupport the Kings Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty in the maintenance and preſervation of his Peace within his Hundred or Franchiſe, and he is called the High-Conſtable, in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect of the Conſtables or Petty-Conſtables, and Headboroughs or Tythingmen, which be in the reſpective Towns, Villages, Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes, or Precincts within his Hundred or Franchiſe under his Juriſdiction; and it is alſo the part and duty of theſe inferior Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, to execute the High-Conſtables office in his abſence, in maintaining and keeping the peace in their ſeveral Tythings and Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mits, and in the High-Conſtables preſence, to be aiding and aſſiſting unto him.</p>
               <p>The High-Conſtables of every Hundred or Rape, or Riding, are choſen by the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices in each County, moſt uſually at their general Quarter Seſſions, or in their ſeveral
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:109137:9"/>diviſions; from the Juſtices they receive their Authority, and are by them again diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged of their office as they ſhall ſee cauſe. At the entrance into their office they take an Oath, the uſual form whereof fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loweth.</p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="oath">
                  <body>
                     <head>The <hi>High-Conſtables</hi> Oath.</head>
                     <p>YOu ſhall ſwear, That you ſhall well and truly ſerve our Sovereign Lord the King in the office of a Conſtable; you ſhall ſee and cauſe his Majeſties peace to be well and truly kept and preſerved according to your power; you ſhall arreſt all ſuch perſons as in your ſight and preſence ſhall ride or go Armed of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenſively, or ſhall commit or make any Riot, Affray, or other breach of his Majeſties peace: you ſhall do your beſt eudeavor (upon complaint to you made) to apprehend all Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lons, Barretors, and Rioters, or perſons Rio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>touſly aſſembled; and if any ſuch Offendors ſhall make reſiſtance (with force,) you ſhall levy Hue and Cry, and ſhall purſue them until they be taken; you ſhall do your beſt endeavour, that the Watch in and about your Hundred be duly kept, for the apprehending of Rogues, Vagabonds, Nightwalkers, Eveſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>droppers, Scouts, and other ſuſpected perſons,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:109137:10"/>and of ſuch as go Armed, and the like; and that Hue and Cry be duly raiſed and pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſued according to the Statute of <hi>Wincheſter,</hi> againſt Murderers, Thieves, and other Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lons; and that the Statutes made for the pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment of Rogues and Vagabonds, and ſuch other idle perſons as come within your bounds and limits be duly put in execution: you ſhall have a watchful eye to ſuch perſons as ſhall maintain or keep any Common houſe or place, where any unlawful Game is or ſhall be uſed; as alſo to ſuch as ſhall frequent or uſe ſuch places, or ſhall uſe or exerciſe any unlawful Games there or elſewhere, contrary to the Statutes. At your Aſſizes, Seſſions of the peace, or Leet, you ſhall preſent all and every the offences done contrary to the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes made <hi>(1 Jacobi, 4 Jacobi, &amp; 21 Jacobi regis,)</hi> to reſtrain the inordinate haunting and tippling in Innes, Alehouſes, and other Victualling houſes, and for repreſſing of Drunkenneſs; you ſhall there likewiſe true Preſentment make of all Bloud ſheddings, Affrayes, Outcryes, Reſcous, and other offences committed or done againſt the Kings Majeſties peace within your Limits: you ſhall once every year during your office Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent at the Quarter Seſſions all Popiſh Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſants within your Liberty, and their
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:109137:10"/>Children above <hi>9.</hi> and their Servants, (<hi>ſc.</hi> their Monthly abſence from the Church) <hi>3 Jac. 4.</hi> you ſhall well and duly execute all Precepts and Warrants to you directed, from the Juſtices of the peace of this County, or higher Officers; you ſhall be ayding to your Neighbours againſt unlawful Purveyances: in time of Hay or Cora harveſt, upon requeſt, you ſhall cauſe all perſons meet to Serve by the day for the Mowing, Reaping or getting in of Corn or Hay; you ſhall in <hi>Eaſter-week</hi> cauſe your Pariſhioners to chuſe Surveyors for the mending of the High-wayes in your Pariſh or Liberty; and you ſhall well and duly according to your knowledge, power and ability, do and execute all other things be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing to the office of a Constable, ſo long as you continue in the ſaid Office.</p>
                     <closer>So help you God.</closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <p>In this Oath is briefly comprehended the whole Duty of a <hi>Conſtable,</hi> and the principal matters of his Office at large.</p>
               <p>I ſhall now ſet forth every particular branch of the Conſtables office, and of the Tythingmen, Headboroughs, Borſholders; their Duties are the ſame in effect, and their Authority: yet the latter are inferiours to the former.</p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="oath">
                  <body>
                     <pb n="8" facs="tcp:109137:11"/>
                     <head>The Form of the Petty-Conſtable or Tything-mans, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Oath is thus.</head>
                     <p>YOu ſhall Swear, That you ſhall well and truly Execute the Office of a Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man of the Tything of <hi>H.</hi> (or Headbo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rough, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>) His Majeſties Peace in your own perſon you ſhall keep, and ſee it kept in all others, as much as in you lyeth. In the preſence of the High-Constable you ſhall be ayding and aſſiſting unto him, and in his ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence you ſhall execute his Office, and do all other thing; belonging to your Office, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to your knowledge and power, until another be choſen in your room, or you be legally diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged thereof.</p>
                     <closer>So help you God.</closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <p>There are in ſeveral Counties of this Realm other Officers; that is, by other Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tles, but not much inferiour to our Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, as in <hi>Warwickſhire</hi> a <hi>Thirdborough,</hi> and in other places a <hi>Boroughead,</hi> in others a <hi>Chief-pledge.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Authority of theſe (as I ſaid) is much like that of the Conſtables, but yet the Office of the Conſtable is diſtinct, and of greater authority and reſpect than theſe.</p>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:109137:11"/>
               <p> 
                  <hi>Lambert,</hi> pag. 51. <hi>&amp;c. Duty of Consta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles,</hi> ſaith, that theſe Tythingmen, Borſhold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> cannot meddle in a Town or Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh where a Conſtable is, becauſe (in com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pariſon of them) the Conſtables be Head<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>offiers, and that the Tythingmen, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are but Aſſiſtants, where the Conſtable is pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent; but in his abſence they are to perform the ſervice, and that there are many things which a Conſtable may do, wherewith the Tythingman and the reſt cannot meddle at all.</p>
               <p>1 <hi>Jac.</hi> cap. 7. <hi>Lambert,</hi> Off. del Conſt. 4, 6, 9. In Towns where there be no Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables, and that the only Officers for the Peace there be, Headboroughs, Thirdbo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>roughs, Borſholders, or ſuch other, and in ſuch caſes where their power and authority is declared to be equal with the Conſtable; in all ſuch things their office is all one in a manner, and divers Statutes do appoint Offendors to be puniſhed by the Conſtable or other inferior officers, which much needs be the Tythingmen, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>12 <hi>H.</hi> 7. f. 8. The High-Conſtables of Hundreds are <hi>Conſervators</hi> of the Peace within their ſeveral Hundreds and Franchiſes at the Common Law.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Brook.</hi> Peace, 13. <hi>Fitz.</hi> 127. All petty
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:109137:12"/>Conſtables by virtue of their office within their ſeveral Liberties of their ſeveral Towns are Conſervators of the Peace at the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Law.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Crompton,</hi> 6.222. 12 <hi>H.</hi> 7. f. 18. Theſe Petty-Conſtables may do what they can to keep the Peace, and <hi>Ex Officio,</hi> they may cauſe ſuch as in their preſence are about to make an Affray, to find Sureties to keep the peace, and that as well before the affray as after.</p>
               <p>3 <hi>H.</hi> 4.9, 10. If a man Aſſault another in the Conſtables preſence, or in his preſence ſhall threaten to kill or beat another, or ſhall be ready to break the peace, the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables or Tythingmen may in ſuch caſes commit the offendors to the Stocks, or other ſafe cuſtody, and after carry them before a Juſtice of the peace, or to Gaol until they find ſecurity for the Peace; which Surety the Conſtables themſelves may take to the uſe of the King.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Term, Trin.</hi> 35 El. <hi>r.</hi> 1458. Karret <hi>ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus</hi> Haumer. The Plaintiff brought an Action of Falſe impriſonment againſt the Defendant for arreſting and impriſoning him, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the Defendant pleaded that he was High-Conſtable of the Hundred of, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in the Couuty of <hi>S.</hi> and that the Plaintiff
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:109137:12"/>made an aſſault in the ſaid Hundred upon one <hi>H. W.</hi> who preſently came to the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant and told him thereof, and ſwore he was in fear of his life of the other; whereupon the Defendant came to the Plaintiff and arreſted and impriſoned him, until he had found ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient ſecurity for the peace; to this the Plaintiff demurred, and it was adjudged that the Defendants plea was inſufficient, 1. be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe he was not preſent at the Aſſault and Affray made; 2. for that he was High-Conſtable of the Hundred, and not Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble of the Town.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Anderſon</hi> Chief Juſtice held (in this caſe) that Conſtables were conſervators of the peace at the Common Law, and ſtill are ſo, and that they ought to preſerve the peace as much as in them lyeth; but that was by parting them who he ſhould ſee breaking of the peace, and carrying them before a Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice to find ſureties to keep the peace, but not to take ſureties himſelf; and if the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable could take ſureties, what ſurety ſhould it be? for he (being no Officer of Record) cannot take Recognizance nor Bayl. But <hi>Walmeſley, Owen,</hi> and <hi>Beaumont,</hi> three other Judges, held that a Conſtable might take Sureties by an obligation, according to the Book of 10 <hi>Edw.</hi> 4. and that the peace was
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:109137:13"/>ſo preſerved by the Conſtables before Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices of peace were; and that the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute which ordained Juſtices, did not take away the authority of the Conſtables.</p>
               <p>Bacon, <hi>Uſe of the Law,</hi> 5, 6. In antient time High-Conſtables of Hundreds, and Petty-Conſtables in every Town were yearly appointed by the Sheriff in his Turn, and were there ſworn.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Direct. Judges,</hi> 29. Conſtables lawfully choſen, if they ſhall refuſe to be ſworn, the Juſtices of the peace may bind them over to the Aſſizes or Seſſions of the Peace, and for ſuch his contempt he is there to be In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicted, fined and impriſoned.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Coke</hi> 8.43. Every perſon that is choſen to be a Conſtable, ought to be <hi>idoneus homo,</hi> a man apt and fit for the Execution of the ſaid Office: And to be <hi>idoneus homo</hi> the Law requireth in him three qualifications, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>Honeſty;</hi> to Execute his Office truly, without malice, affection, or partiality.</p>
               <p n="2">2. <hi>Knowledge;</hi> to underſtand his Duty, what he ought to do.</p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>Ability;</hi> as well in Eſtate as in Body, that ſo he may attend, and execute his Office diligently, and not neglect the ſame, through want or impotency.</p>
               <p>For ſuch as are choſen out of the meaner
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:109137:13"/>ſort, are either ignorant what to do, or ſtand in awe of the greater; ſo that they dare not do what they ought, or elſe are not able to ſpare time; Therefore they ought to be choſen out of the better ſort of Pariſhioners, and not either by the Houſe, or other Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtome.</p>
               <p>If a man be choſen Conſtable, not able and qualified as aforeſaid, he may be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged of his ſaid Office by Law, and ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther fit man appointed in his place.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Co.</hi> 8.42. If Leets chooſe unable or unfit Petty-Conſtables, it is cauſe of forfeiture of the Leet, and ſuch choice is void.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. cap. 12. Two Juſtices of the peace may appoint, and ſwear new <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables, Headboroughs,</hi> &amp;c. in caſe of death or removal of ſuch Officers out of the pariſh; And, if in default of holding Court-Leets they continue above the year, they may be diſcharged at the Seſſions, and others put in.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Idem Stat.</hi> Conſtables, Headboroughs and Tythingmen which are out of purſe for their charges, they may with the Churchwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Overſeers of the poor and other officers of the Pariſh, make Rates upon all occupiers of Lands and inhabitants, and all others chargeable to the Poor, by the <hi>Stat.</hi> 42 <hi>El.</hi> which being confirmed under the
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:109137:14"/>Hands and Seals of two Juſtices of the peace, may by their Warrants be levied by diſtreſs and ſale of the Goods of ſuch as refuſe to pay the ſame.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="chapter">
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. II.</hi> The duty of Conſtables and Headbe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>roughs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in Executing of War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants directed to them from the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stices of the peace, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>THe Conſtable or other ſworn Officer to whom any Warrant ſhall be directed and delivered, ought with all ſpeed and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crecy, to ſeek and find out the party, and then to Execute his ſaid Warrant.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Br. Faux, impriſ.</hi> 23. A known ſworn Officer (be he Sheriff, Underſheriff, Bayliff, or Conſtable, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>) needs not to ſhew his Warrant to a man when he comes to ſerve it upon him, though he demandeth it; but if the Juſtice will direct his Warrant to his ſervant, or to another (who is no ſworn Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer) to ſerve it, they muſt ſhew their War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant to the party if he demand it, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:109137:14"/>the party may make reſiſtance, and needs not to obey it.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Co.</hi> 6.54. &amp; 9.68. A ſworn and known Officer, if he will not ſhew his Warrant, yet he ought to declare to the party the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents thereof upon ſerving it.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Co.</hi> 9.69. An Officer giveth ſufficient notice what he is when he ſaith to the party, <hi>I Arreſt you in the Kings name,</hi> &amp;c. and in ſuch caſe the party at his peril ought to obey him, though he knoweth him not to be an Officer; and if he have no lawful Warrant the party grieved may have his Action of Falſe impriſonment againſt him.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dyer,</hi> 244. <hi>Stat.</hi> 43. El. <hi>cap.</hi> 6. If a Conſtable or other officer do Arreſt a man for the Peace, or the like, before he hath any Warrant, and then afterwards doth procure a Warrant (or a Warrant cometh after to him) to Arreſt the party for the ſame cauſe, the firſt arreſt was unlawful, and the Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer is lyable to an Action of Falſe Impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
               <p>10 <hi>E.</hi> 4. fol. 12. Br. <hi>Falſe Impriſ.</hi> 38. Where a Warrant is granted againſt <hi>I. H.</hi> the ſon of <hi>T. H.</hi> and the Officer thereupon arreſteth <hi>I. H.</hi> the ſon of <hi>W. H.</hi> although in truth he be the ſame perſon that offended, and againſt whom the complaint was made,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:109137:15"/>yet this Arreſt is wrongful, and the Officer is ſubject to an Action of Falſe Impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Cromp.</hi> 214. a. <hi>&amp;</hi> 148. <hi>Crooke</hi> 144.53. If a Conſtable, or any other perſon hath ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſted a man by virtue of his Warrant, which he hath from a Juſtice of the peace, and then taketh his word that he will come to him again, at another time, to go with him to the Juſtice according to his Warrant, (and ſo letteth the party go) who comes not again at the time appointed, it ſeems the Officer cannot afterwards arreſt or take him again by force of his former warrant, becauſe this was done by the conſent of the Officer; But if the party arreſted had eſcaped (of his own wrong) without the conſent of the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficer, the Officer may take him again and again upon freſh ſuit, ſo often as he eſcapeth, although he be out of view, or that he fly into another Town or County.</p>
               <p>When an Officer hath received a warrant, he is bound to obſerve and purſue the effect of his Warrant in every behalf and particular; or otherwiſe his warrant will not excuſe him of that which he hath done.</p>
               <p>21 <hi>H.</hi> 7.39. If a Conſtable or other of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficer having a lawful warrant to Arreſt ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and he ſhall be reſiſted or aſſaulted by
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:109137:15"/>the party, or by any other perſon, then may that Officer juſtifie the beating or hurting of ſuch perſons, and others (upon his requeſt) may, and ought to aid him.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>H.</hi> 8.16. <hi>Br.</hi> Faux Imp. 8. <hi>Lamb.</hi> 67.94. <hi>Co.</hi> 10.76. <hi>Cromp.</hi> 74. If a Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice of peace ſhall iſſue out any Warrant for a matter wherein he hath Juriſdiction, although it be beyond his Authority, yet it is not diſputable by the Conſtable or other ſuch officer, but muſt be obeyed and exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted by the Conſtable or other officer to whom it is brought: As if a Juſtice of peace ſhall ſend forth his Warrant to arreſt one for the peace or good behaviour, without cauſe, the officer that ſerves this warrant ſhall not be puniſhed for the executing thereof; but if a Juſtice of peace ſhall make his warrant to do a thing out of his juriſdiction, or in a cauſe wherein the Juſtice of peace is no Judge, if the Officer ſhall ſerve ſuch a War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant, here he is puniſhable; for the Officer is not bound to obey him who is not Judge of the Cauſe, no more than a mere ſtranger, for the Officer is bound to take notice of the authority and juriſdiction of the Judge.</p>
               <p>But if any Juſtice ſends his warrant to a Conſtable or any other officer to bring him to anſwer all ſuch matters as ſhall be
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:109137:16"/>objected againſt him, and doth not ſpecifie the cauſe in his Warrant wherefore he iſſued forth the ſame, this Warrant is unlawful, and the Officer is liable to an Action of Falſe impriſonment, if he executes it.</p>
               <p>So, if a Juſtice of peace ſend a Warrant to take one for Cozenage, to take and bring to a Juſtice or to Gaol, one that another doth ſuſpect for Felony, where the matter is ſmall, or the ſuſpition ſlight, or to licenſe a petty Chapman to ſell from houſe to houſe, to ſend a poor body to a place otherwiſe than the Law directs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſuch kind of Warrants are not warrantable.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Cook,</hi> Iuſtit. part 4. tit. <hi>De frangent. Priſon'.</hi> All Warrants not ſpecifying the Cauſe, are utterly againſt Law.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Except for Treaſon, or Warrants from the Council, Secretaries of State, or Lord Chief Juſtice; theſe need not ſet forth the Cauſe for reaſons of State.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Cromp.</hi> 149. If any man ſhall contemn or abuſe the Juſtice of peace his Warrant, as by caſting it into the dirt, or treading it un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der his feet, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſuch offendor may be bound to his good behavior for it, and be Indicted and Fined; it being a contempt againſt the Kings proceſs.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="chapter">
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:109137:16"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. III.</hi> Articles which the High-Conſtables are to return unto the Juſtices at their Seſſions or monthly meetings of their Diviſions, and to cauſe their Petty-Conſtables, Headboroughs, and Ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thingmen in their ſeveral Liberties to make Return thereof unto them.</head>
               <p n="1">1. THey are to return the Names, Sir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>names, additions of names and qualities of all Popiſh Recuſants (as well houſe-keepers as lodgers) dwelling or reſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding in any of their ſaid Pariſhes, Liberties, or Precincts.</p>
               <p n="2">2. Such perſons as ſhall continue drink<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing or tipling in any Innes or Ale-houſes at any time, and more eſpecially upon the Lords day, or Holidayes, and ſuch perſons as they ſhall find drunk, and all ſuch Inn-keepers and Alehouſe-keepers as ſhall entertain them.</p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>Item,</hi> The names of ſuch as ſhall pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phanely Swear or Curſe, with the number of their Oaths, immediately after the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitting
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:109137:17"/>ſuch offence, inform the next Juſtice thereof.</p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi>Item,</hi> They are to Return ſuch Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctualers or Alehouſe-keepers as uſe victu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>aling or ſelling of Beer and Ale without Licenſe.</p>
               <p n="5">5. <hi>Item,</hi> Such perſons as ſuffer any un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawful Games to be ſuffered in their houſes, backſides, or gardens; and alſo the Names of ſuch as ſhall play at any of the ſaid Games.</p>
               <p n="6">6. <hi>Item,</hi> Such perſons as refuſe or neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect to do their duty of Watching and Ward<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing.</p>
               <p n="7">7. <hi>Item,</hi> Such perſons as divide their houſes into ſeveral Tenements, and ſuch as do entertain <hi>Inmates</hi> who may be an annoy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance to their neighbours, or likely to bring charge upon the Pariſh.</p>
               <p n="8">8. <hi>Item,</hi> The defaults of Petty-Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles and Tythingmen, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for not cauſing rogues, vagabonds and beggars to be duly apprehended, puniſhed, and paſſed according to the Statute.</p>
               <p n="9">9. <hi>Item,</hi> All Maſterleſs men and wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men living at their own hands, ſuch as are idle and will not labour, and can give no good Account how they get their living, all Suſpitious perſons, Whores, <hi>Nocti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vagants</hi>
                  <pb n="21" facs="tcp:109137:17"/>or Night-walkers, and Mothers of Baſtards, which may be chargeable to the Pariſh.</p>
               <p n="10">10. <hi>Item,</hi> The names of ſuch perſons as refuſe to take Apprentices poor Pariſh-children to Husbandry, and other callings according to Law.</p>
               <p n="11">11. <hi>Item,</hi> All ſuch as neglect to make due Rates and Collections for the relief of the Poor in every pariſh, and that cannot, or do not give a juſt Account of the employ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the Rent and Stock of the Poor.</p>
               <p n="12">12. <hi>Item,</hi> Of the defects in the High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes and Bridges, with the names of ſuch as ſhould repair them, and have neglected or refuſed to do their duty herein.</p>
               <p n="13">13. <hi>Item,</hi> Such Scavengers as neglect to do their office in cleanſing the Streets, to be kept clean within their Liberties; and the names of ſuch perſons as commit common Annoyances, by laying of dung, ſoyl, dirt, or aſhes in the Street.</p>
               <p n="14">14. <hi>Item,</hi> The names of all ſuch perſons as refuſe to Pave the Streets before their houſes, where the ſaid ſtreets have uſually been paved formerly.</p>
               <p n="15">15. <hi>Item,</hi> The names of all ſuch perſons as keep any Hogs (to the common Annoy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of his Majeſties ſubjects) in or about
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:109137:18"/>ſuch Liberties, places, and precincts where Hogs ought not to be kept.</p>
               <p n="16">16. <hi>Item,</hi> All ſuch Bakers as put light Bread to ſale, and the weight thereof; and ſuch Brewers as ſell Beer or Ale to unlicenſed Alehouſe-keepers; all Foreſtallers, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grators, and ingroſſers of any Corn, Grain, Butter, Cheeſe, Bacon, or any other kind of dead Victuals whatſoever.</p>
               <p n="17">17. Laſtly, All ſuch perſons as can prove or teſtifie any of the ſaid Offences, are to be warned to appear before the ſaid Juſtices at their Seſſions or meetings aforeſaid, to teſtifie their knowledge of ſuch Offences of which they can give Information.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="chapter">
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. IV.</hi> The duty of Conſtables, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> touching Watching, Warding, Rogues, Vaga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bonds, Hue and Cry, carrying Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoners to the Gaol, Servants and La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bourers.</head>
               <p>13 <hi>EDu.</hi> 1. cap. 4. <hi>Dalt.</hi> ch. 60. f. 140. <hi>Poul.</hi> Watch. 1. A Watch is to be kept in every Town, Pariſh, Village, and
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:109137:18"/>Tything, every night from <hi>Aſcenſion</hi> till <hi>Michaelmas,</hi> from Sun-ſet to Sun-riſe, which the Conſtables, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> muſt conſtantly cauſe to be ſet, and that by two or four men, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the greatneſs of the place.</p>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>Dalton,</hi> ch. 60. fol. 140. 5 <hi>Ed.</hi> 3.14. 5 <hi>H.</hi> 7.5. Theſe Watchmen are to appre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hend and examine all ſtrangers that paſs by them in the night, and if they find cauſe of ſuſpition in them, then they may ſecure them till the morning; and if the parties re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe to obey the Watchmen, they may levy <hi>Hue and Cry</hi> to take them, and upon their reſiſtance the Watchmen may juſtifie the beating of them, and ſet them in the Stocks or Cage till morning; and then if no ſuſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion be found in the parties, they may let them go. But if there be found ſuſpition in them, then the Watchmen may deliver them to the Conſtable, or Tythingman, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> who is to convey them before a Juſtice of peace, who after Examination of them, may bind them over, commit or acquit them as he ſhall ſee cauſe. Theſe Watchmen are alſo to apprehend all ſuch as ride or go armed, and all Rogues, Vagabonds, Noctivagants, Nightwalkers, Eveſdroppers, Scouts, and ſuch like.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. <hi>chap.</hi> 60. <hi>fol.</hi> 141. Theſe
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:109137:19"/>three particulars following have been held for Law concerning <hi>Watches,</hi> viz.</p>
               <list>
                  <item>1. The Watchmen muſt be men of body, well and ſufficiently armed, <hi>(not with a Prong, as the Countrey faſhion is)</hi> and no man is compellable to Watch, unleſs he be an inhabitant within the ſame Town or Pariſh, where he is required to Watch.</item>
                  <item>2. Such as are Inhabitants within the Town are not compellable to Watch at the will of the Conſtable, but only when their turn comes, according to the uſe and cuſtome of the place; which is moſt commonly by Turn or Houſe.</item>
                  <item>3. Dalton, <hi>Ibid.</hi> It hath been held by ſome, That if a man who is compel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lable to Watch, ſhall contemptuouſly refuſe to Watch upon command of the Conſtable, that in ſuch caſe the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable might <hi>(ex Officio)</hi> ſet the party in the Stocks for his contempt.</item>
               </list>
               <p>But the ſafeſt way is, for the Conſtable to preſent ſuch perſon for his default at the Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſizes or Seſſions of the Peace, or elſe to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plain of him to a Juſtice of the peace, who may bind the offendor to the good behaviour,
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:109137:19"/>and ſo over to the next Quarter-Seſſions, there to anſwer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="2">2. 39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 4. <hi>Wingat</hi>'s Stat. tit. <hi>Vagabonds.</hi> Reſolu. Judges, <hi>ſect.</hi> 717. <hi>Bolſtr.</hi> 2. part. <hi>Rep.</hi> f. 258. The Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, Tythingman, or Headborough, aſſiſted by the Miniſter and one other of the Pariſh, is to ſee (or do it himſelf) Rogues and Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gabonds, which ſhall be taken begging, ſtrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ped naked, from the middle upwards, and openly whipped till their body be bloody, and then forthwith to be ſent away from pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh to pariſh, or tything to tything, the next ſtraight way to the place of their birth; and if that cannot be known, then to the place where they laſt dwelt by the ſpace of one whole year, before ſuch puniſhment; and if that cannot be known, then to the Town through which they laſt paſſed un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puniſhed; and when they come there, if it cannot be diſcovered where they were born, or laſt dwelt as aforeſaid, then are they by that Conſtable to be conveyed to the Houſe of correction or common Gaol of that County, to be employed in work, or placed in ſome ſervice, and ſo to continue by the ſpace of one year; or in caſe they be not able in body, that Town is to keep them, till they may be placed in
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:109137:20"/>ſome Alms-houſe within the ſame Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalton,</hi> f. 129. After ſuch puniſhment, the Vagabond is to have a Teſtimonial under the hand and ſeal of the Conſtable, Tythingman, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and the Miniſter of the place, teſtifying the day and place of his pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment, the place to which he is to be conveyed, and the time limited for his paſſage thither; which time if by his own default he Exceeds, he ſhall incurr the like puniſhment from time to time, till he arrive at the place limited. The ſubſtance of the Teſtimonial is to be entred by the Miniſter in a Regiſter-book, which he is to keep for that purpoſe, on pain of 5. ſhillings.</p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="testimonial">
                  <body>
                     <head>The form of a <hi>Teſtimonial</hi> for Conveying a Rogue, or Vagabond.</head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>W.W.</hi> A ſturdy vagrant Beggar (aged about <hi>40</hi> years) tall of ſtature, red haired, and long lean viſaged, and ſquint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eyed, was this <hi>24</hi> day of <hi>A.</hi> in the <hi>22</hi> year of the Reign of our gracious Sovereign Lord King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> openly whipped at <hi>T.</hi> in the County of <hi>G.</hi> according to the Law for a wandring Rogue, and is aſſigned to paſs forthwith from pariſh to pariſh, by the Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:109137:20"/>thereof the next ſtraight way to <hi>W.</hi> in the County of <hi>B.</hi> where he confeſſeth he was born; and he is limited to be at <hi>W.</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, within twelve dayes now next enſuing, at his peril.</p>
                     <closer>
                        <dateline>Given under the hands and ſeals of <hi>C. W.</hi> Miniſter of <hi>T.</hi> aforeſaid, and of <hi>J. G.</hi> Conſtable there, the day and year aforeſaid.</dateline>
                     </closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <p>A Juſtice of peace alone may under his hand and ſeal make ſuch Teſtimonial. <hi>Lam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert,</hi> 206.</p>
               <p>39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> cap. 4. <hi>Dalt.</hi> ch. 47. fol. 128. <hi>Reſolu. Judges,</hi> ſect. 13, 14. If any Conſtable, Tythingman, or Headborough be found negligent in the due Execution of the Act of the 39. of <hi>Eliz.</hi> aforeſaid, he for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feits ten Shillings for every default: And ſuch perſons as ſhall hinder the execution of the Law upon Rogues, forfeit five Pounds, and are to be bound to the good behaviour; and if a Conſtable refuſe to receive a Rogue, and to convey him or her to the next, or if he do receive him and not convey him to the next Conſtable, he forfeits five Pounds, and may be bound to the good beha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viour.</p>
               <p>1 <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 7. <hi>Dalt.</hi> ch. 47. fol. 128. <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolu. Judg.</hi> ſect. 13, 14. Every perſon
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:109137:21"/>ſhall apprehend or cauſe to be apprehended ſuch Rogues as he ſhall ſee or know to reſort to his houſe to beg, or receive any alms, and him or them ſhall carry, or cauſe to be carried to the next Conſtable; or elſe ſhall forfeit, for every ſuch default ten Shillings; and the Conſtable is to whip and convey ſuch Rogues as before is directed on pain of twenty Shillings.</p>
               <p>39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> cap. 4. <hi>Dalt.</hi> ch. 47. fol. 149. 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 7. Two Juſtices of peace, (one of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) by Warrant under their hands and ſeals may cauſe to be levied, by diſtreſs and ſale of the Offendors goods, all the Fines and forfeitures aforeſaid after con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viction of the party; which muſt be either by Confeſſion of the party, or proof of two Witneſſes before the ſaid Juſtices.</p>
               <p>7 <hi>Jac.</hi> chap. 4. Conſtables or Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men neglecting to ſearch for Rogues upon the Juſtices warrant, or to appear at their meeting to give an account what Rogues have been puniſhed, or ſent to the Houſe of Correction; or if they neglect to convey ſuch to the Houſe of Correction as by War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant are to be ſent thither, they are lyable to ſuch Fine as the Juſtices pleaſe, not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding forty Shillings.</p>
               <p>1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 7.14. <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 12. Any
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:109137:21"/>Juſtice of the peace may reward any perſon or perſons who ſhall apprehend, and bring be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore him any Rogue, Vagabond, or ſturdy Beggar, by granting to ſuch perſon a Warrant under his hand and ſeal, to the Conſtable or Tythingman of the place through which the Rogue did paſs un-apprehended; ordering the ſaid Conſtable, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to give ſuch perſon two ſhillings for every Rogue ſo taken: And if the Conſtable, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> refuſe to pay it, the Juſtices of the peace may proceed againſt ſuch Officers according to the Stat. 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 7. and compel him to pay his For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture by the ſaid Statute, and to allow the ſaid two ſhillings out of the ſaid Forfeiture to ſuch perſon, with ſuch further allowance for loſs of time, as the Juſtice ſhall think fit.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 12. If any perſon ſhall apprehend any Rogue at the confines of any County, which paſſed through any Pariſh of another County un-apprehended, then the perſon ſo apprehending ſuch Rogue muſt carry him to ſome Juſtice of peace of the County through which he paſſed un-apprehended, who (upon a Certificate under the hand of ſome Juſtice of peace of the County where ſuch Rogue was apprehen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded) is to grant his Warrant to the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble,
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:109137:22"/>
                  <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to pay two ſhillings as aforeſaid; which if he refuſe or neglect, then the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice is to proceed againſt the Conſtable, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and cauſe him to pay ten Shillings to the party, or ſo much thereof for loſs of time as the Juſtice ſhall think fit.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. cap. 12. It is Enacted, That whereas Conſtables, Tythingmen, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are at great charges in Relieving, carrying with Paſſes, and conveying Rogues, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> all Conſtables, Tythingmen, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſo out of purſe, with the Churchwardens and Overſeers of the Poor, and other inhabitants of the Pariſh may make a Rate, and tax all the Inhabitants of the Pariſh which are Chargeable by the 43. of <hi>Eliz.</hi> which Rate muſt be confirmed under the hands and ſeals of two Juſtices of the peace: And if any perſon refuſe to pay his Rate, then the Conſtable by warrant from two Juſtices of peace, may levy the ſame upon the Goods of the party re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſing, rendring them the Overplus, if any remain thereof.</p>
               <p>39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> cap. 4. &amp; 17. 43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> cap. 2. 1 <hi>Jacobi,</hi> cap. 7. 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> cap. 28. 7 <hi>Jac.</hi> cap. 24. 5 <hi>Elizab.</hi> cap. 4. <hi>Dalt.</hi> cap. 47. fol. 123, 124, 125. All theſe perſons hereafter named are accounted and adjudged Rogues, Vagabonds, and ſturdy Beggars:
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:109137:22"/>That is to ſay, all ſuch perſons above the age of ſeven years, Man or Woman, ſole or covert, that wander from their uſual place of abode, abroad, every where begging; or if they do not beg, yet if they wander and loyter about without a lawful Paſport, and give no good account for their travel, are accounted Rogues.</p>
               <p>All Scholars, and Sea-faring men which beg, Wandring perſons that uſe unlawful Games, ſubtil craft, or Playes, or pretending themſelves to have skill in Phyſiognomie, Palmeſtrie, or the like; or to be Fortune<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tellers, or Figure-caſters.</p>
               <p>All Proctors, Patent-gatherers (except for Fire) Collectors for Gaols, Priſoners, or Hoſpitals, wandring abroad; Fencers, Bearwards, (thoſe are Rogues in grain) common Players of Interludes, and Fidlers or Minſtrels wandring abroad.</p>
               <p>All Juglers (<hi>Hocus pocus,</hi> and Slight-of-hand Artiſts,) Tinkers, Pedlars, and Petry-Chapmen, and Glaſs men wandring abroad, eſpecially if they be not well known, or have not a ſufficient Teſtimonial; all counterfeit <hi>Egyptians,</hi> not being Felons; all perſons de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livered out of Gaols, which beg for their fees, or otherwiſe do travel begging; ſuch as go to or from the Bathes and do not purſue
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:109137:23"/>their Licenſe, Souldiers and Mariners that beg, and counterfeit a Certificate of their Commanders.</p>
               <p>All Labourers which wander abroad out of the Pariſh, and refuſe to work for wages reaſonably taxed, having no living otherwiſe to maintain themſelves; and ſuch as go with a General paſport which is not directed from pariſh to pariſh.</p>
               <p>All theſe are accounted Rogues, Vaga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bonds, and ſturdy Beggars.</p>
               <p>All Servants that depart out of their ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, (<hi>viz.</hi> out of one City, Town, or Pariſh to another, or out of one Hundred or County to ſerve in another) without a Teſtimonial, or with a falſe one; and ſuch perſons as are ſick of the Plague, and wilfully go abroad in company againſt the command of Officers, are to be puniſhed as Vagabonds; but none are to be ſent to the place of birth or laſt ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitation, but wandring Rogues; thoſe which beg in their own Pariſh, or in the High-ways (without the appointment of the Overſeers) are to be ſent to the Houſe of Correction.</p>
               <p>39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> cap. 4. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 47. fol. 135. <hi>Reſolu, Judges,</hi> ſect. 4, 5. A Wife and Children under ſeven years of age being vagrant, muſt be placed with the Husband; and if the Husband be dead, then with the
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:109137:23"/>Wife where ſhe was born or laſt dwelt; and vagrant Children above ſeven years of age muſt be ſent to the place of their birth; and if the vagrant Parents with their Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren, under ſeven years of age, be placed at the place of birth of the Parents, or at the laſt place of dwelling; if afterwards the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rents or either of them dye, or run away, yet the Children once ſetled, muſt remain there ſtill, and may not be ſent to the place of their birth, though afterwards they attain to the age of ſeven years.</p>
               <p>The Wife being but a vagrant Rogue, ought to be ſent to her Husband, though he be but a ſervant in another Town or Pariſh; and the Rogue, whoſe place or dwelling cannot be known, having Wife or Children under ſeven years of age, they muſt go with the Husband to the place where they were laſt ſuffered to paſs through unpuniſhed; where the Children muſt be relieved with the work of their Parents, though their Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rents be committed to the Houſe of Corre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction.</p>
               <p n="3">3. Hue and Cry. <hi>Dalton</hi> J. P. ch. 28. fol. 75. The Conſtables, or Tythingmen of every Town, Pariſh, or Village, to whom <hi>Hue and Cry</hi> ſhall come, ought to ſearch in all ſuſpected houſes and places within their
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:109137:24"/>Liberties, and as well be Officers, as all other perſons which ſhall purſue the Hue and Cry, may take and ſtay all ſuch perſons, as in their ſearch and purſuit they ſhall find to be ſuſpitious, and ſhall carry them be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ſome Juſtice of the County where they are taken to be Examined, where they were at the time of the Felony committed; and if any default be in the Officers, they may be fined by the Juſtices for their neglect.</p>
               <p>27 <hi>Elizab.</hi> cap. 13. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 48. fol. 132. Where a Hundred is ſued for a Robbery, and damages are recovered againſt one or ſome few inhabitants of the Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred, and the reſt refuſe to contribute thereunto; in ſuch caſe two Juſtices of the peace (one of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) dwelling within or near the Hundred, may for the levying thereof ſet a Tax upon every Pariſh within that Hundred; according to which the Conſtables, or Tythingmen of every pariſh muſt Tax the particular Inhabitants within their Liberties, and then levy the money upon ſuch as refuſe by diſtreſs and ſale of their Goods, reſtoring the over-plus if any be, and after the Money is gathered, they are to reſtore the ſame to the Juſtices, or ſome of them that made the Rate within ten dayes.</p>
               <pb n="35" facs="tcp:109137:24"/>
               <p> 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> cap. 13. That Hundred where freſh Suit ſhall ceaſe, ſhall anſwer half the damages to the Hundred where the Felony was committed, to be recovered in any Court at <hi>Westminſter,</hi> in the name of the Clerk of the Peace of the County where the Felony was committed; in which caſe the death or change of the Clerk of the Peace ſhall not abate the Suit: And this Recovery is to be taxed and levied as the former.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Bract.</hi> lib. 3. f. 121. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. f. 133. Where any one of the Robbers is apprehen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, or where the Action is not proſecuted within one year after the Robbery commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, the Hundred is not chargeable for the Robbery; Obſerve likewiſe, that the Hue and Cry ſhall not be judged legal, unleſs the purſuit be both by horſe and foot.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Weſtm.</hi> 1. ch. 9. <hi>Co.</hi> 2. part Inſt. f. 172. He that goeth not at the command of the Sheriff or Conſtable at the Cry of the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, that is, upon <hi>Hue and Cry,</hi> to arreſt Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lons after Attainder, ſhall be grievouſly fined and impriſoned.</p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi>Carrying Priſoners to the Gaol.</hi> 3 Jac. ch. 10. <hi>Dalt.</hi> chap. 43. f. 104. An of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendorwhich is to be conveyed to Gaol, muſt bear all charges both of himſelf and of thoſe that guard him, if he be able; and if he
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:109137:25"/>refuſe to pay the charges, or ſhall not at the time of the commitment diſcharge the ſame, then upon a Warrant from a Juſtice of peace, the Conſtable of the Liberty or Town where the offendor hath any Goods (being within the ſame County) may ſell ſo many of the parties Goods, as in the diſcretion of the Juſtice ſhall be thought ſufficient to ſatisfie the ſaid Charges, the Apprizement to be made by four Inhabitants of the pariſh where ſuch Goods be, and the over-plus to be returned to the owner.</p>
               <p>1 <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 10. And if the offendor have no goods to defray the charges, then the charge muſt be born by the Town or Pariſh where the offendor was taken; which muſt be done by Tax, made by the Conſtable, Churchwardens, and two or three other In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitants; and where there are no ſuch of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers, then four of the principal Inhabitants of the pariſh muſt make the Rate, which being allowed under the hand of a Juſtice of peace, every Inhabitant muſt pay their pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion, according to the ſaid Rate; and if any refuſe to pay, the Conſtable, Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, or other officer by Warrant from a Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice of the peace, may levy the ſame by diſtreſs, (and after appraiſement by four of the Inhabitants) may ſell the ſame;
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:109137:25"/>rendring to the party refuſing the overplus, if any be.</p>
               <p>And if the Conſtable or other officer that makes ſuch diſtreſs be ſued, he may plead Juſtification, and upon a verdict for the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant, or Non-ſuit of the plaintiff, he ſhall recover treble damages, beſides Coſts of ſuit.</p>
               <p n="5">5. <hi>Servants</hi> and <hi>Labourers,</hi> 5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> c. 14. The Conſtable in the time of Hay and Corn harveſt, upon requeſt to him made, by any man that wants Labourers, to get in his Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veſt to prevent loſs thereof, may cauſe all ſuch Artificers as he ſhall ſee meet to la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour, to ſerve by the day for mowing, reap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or otherwiſe, for the getting in of Corn or Hay abroad, according as they ſeem fit and able to perform. And if ſuch perſons ſhall refuſe to work, after they are requeſted thereunto, the Conſtable may ſet them in the Stocks by the ſpace of two days and one night; and if the Conſtable neglect to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form his office herein, he forfeits Fourty ſhillings.</p>
               <p>5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> chap. 4. No perſon reteined in Husbandry, or in any Arts appointed by that Statute, ſhall depart after the time of ſuch re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teiner expired, out of the City, Town, or Pariſh where he laſt ſerved, to ſerve in an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:109137:26"/>without a Teſtimonial, (<hi>viz.</hi> in a Town-corporate under the hands and ſeals of the Magiſtrate, and two houſholders there; and in the Countrey under the hands and ſeals of the Conſtable (or other officers,) and two houſholders of the Town or Pariſh where he laſt ſerved,) which Teſtimonial is to be regiſtred by the Miniſter, for which he is to have Two pence, and then to be deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered to the party.</p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="testimonial">
                  <body>
                     <head>The form of a <hi>Teſtimonial</hi> for a <hi>Servant.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>MEmorandum,</hi> That <hi>J.S.</hi> ſervant to <hi>J.D.</hi> of <hi>Bramſil</hi> in the County of <hi>Southam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pton</hi> yeoman, is licenſed to depart from his ſaid Maſter, and is at liberty to ſerve elſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where; according to the Statute in that caſe made and provided. In witneſs whereof we have hereunto ſet our hands and ſeals this <hi>25</hi> day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in the <hi>22</hi> year of the reign of our gracious Sovereign Lord King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second <hi>1670.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>
                           <list>
                              <item>
                                 <hi>Ri. Turner,</hi> Conſtable of <hi>Bramſil.</hi>
                              </item>
                              <item>
                                 <hi>R. C.</hi>
                              </item>
                              <item>
                                 <hi>J. D.</hi> Houſholders there.</item>
                           </list>
                        </signed>
                     </closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <pb n="39" facs="tcp:109137:26"/>
               <p> If it be one that lives with a Woman, then ſay (<hi>is licenſed to depart from his Miſtreſs or Dame,</hi> as ſhe is;) if the Maſter be not a Yeoman or Husbandman, but an handy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crafts-man, as Taylor, Smith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> then name him ſo in the Teſtimonial.</p>
               <p>5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 4. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 31. fo. 63. The Maſter that reteins a Servant without ſuch a Teſtimonial, forfeits Five pounds, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing thereof convicted by Indictment taken in the Seſſions of the Peace; and every Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant which ſheweth not ſuch a Teſtimonial to the chief Officer in a Corporation, or to the Conſtable or other officer, Miniſter or Churchwarden of the place where he is to dwell, may be impriſoned until he procure one, and if he produce not one within one and twenty dayes next after the firſt day of his Impriſonment, or if he ſhall ſhew a falſe or counterfeit one, then he is to be whipped, and uſed as a Vagabond.</p>
               <p>This Statute, as to this particular of Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monials, is now grown in a manner quite ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolete, ſo ſeldom uſed, that it's ſcarce known, although the penalty in the ſame be ſtrict and ſevere, yet it is of good uſe; and ſo are a great many penal Statutes more very bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficial to the Commonwealth, if they were duly put in Execution, eſpecially thoſe
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:109137:27"/>enacted to puniſh the daily offences of Brewers, Bakers, Alehouſes; all ſuch as uſe Weights or Meaſures, Millers, Foreſtallers, Ingroſſers, Regrators, <hi>cum multis aliis, &amp;c.</hi> theſe are the Caterpillars of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="chapter">
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. V.</hi> The duty of Conſtables, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> about Affrayes, Riots, Routs, Armes, Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>litia, Eſcapes, Forcible entries, the Peace, Hedge breakers, Setting<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dogs.</head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>AFfrayes, Riots, Routs.</hi> 3 H. 4.9, <hi>&amp;</hi> 10. <hi>Bacon</hi>'s Uſe of the Law, fol. 5. <hi>Dalton,</hi> J. P. ch. 1. fol. 4, 5. If one makes an Affray or Aſſault upon another in a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables preſence, or in his preſence ſhall threaten to kill, beat, or hurt another, or ſhall be in a fury, ready to break the peace; In theſe caſes the Conſtable may commit the offendors to the ſtocks, or to ſome other ſafe cuſtody for the preſent, until ſuch time as he can carry them before ſome Juſtice of the peace, or to the Gaol, until they find
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:109137:27"/>Sureties for the peace: The Conſtable may take ſecurity for the peace by Obligation to be ſealed and delivered to the Kings uſe, which Bond the Conſtable was to ſend to the Exchequer or Chancery, from whence the proceſs ſhould iſſue to levy the debt to the Kings uſe if the peace were broken. This was the opinion of three of the Judges of the Common Pleas, in <hi>Skirret</hi>'s Caſe: <hi>Trin.</hi> 35 <hi>Eliz.</hi> com. ban. Rot. 1458. But <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſon</hi> Chief Juſtice ſaid, That the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable ought to carry the party that he ſhould ſee breaking of the peace, before a Juſtice to find ſureties for the peace, which is the uſual practice at this day.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 8. fol. 33. The Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble where he ſeeth an affray made, or ſuch as are about to make an affray, ought to command the Affrayers in the Kings name to ſurceaſe and depart on pain of Impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; and if a Conſtable being preſent at an affray, doth not his beſt endeavour to part them, it being preſented by the Jury at the Seſſions of the Peace, ſuch Conſtable may be fined for it.</p>
               <p>3 <hi>H.</hi> 7.1. 3 <hi>H.</hi> 7.20. <hi>Lambert,</hi> 136. 38 <hi>E.</hi> 3.8. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 8. fol. 33. If any one be dangerouſly hurt in an Affray, the Conſtable or any other may ſtay the offendor,
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:109137:28"/>and carry him to a Juſtice of peace, who is either to bayl him till the next Gaol-delivery; or to commit him to the Gaol, until it be known whether the party will live or dye thereof.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Lambert,</hi> 135. 1 <hi>H.</hi> 7.7. 3 <hi>H.</hi> 7.10. If Affrayers will not depart, but do draw weapons, or give any blow, the Conſtable may command aſſiſtance of others to ceaſe the Affray; and if they make reſiſtance, may juſtifie the beating and wounding of them: and if the Conſtable or any of his aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtants be killed, it is murder in the Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frayers.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Lambert,</hi> 135. 7 <hi>E.</hi> 3.19. Where there is a great and dangerous Affray, the Conſtable may make proclamation in the Kings name, that the Affrayers ſhall keep the Kings peace, and depart: and if the Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fray be in a houſe, the Conſtable may break into the houſe (if the doors be ſhut) to ſee the Peace kept, though none of the parties have taken any hurt; and if the Affrayers fly into another mans houſe, the Conſtable upon freſh purſuit, may break into ſuch houſe and apprehend them.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> ch. 8. fo. 34. &amp; ch. 118. fol. 340. <hi>Crompt.</hi> 146. b. &amp; 172. b. Where the Affrayers fly into another County, the
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:109137:28"/>Conſtable ſeeing it may freſhly purſue, or cauſe them to be purſued and taken there: and then the Conſtable may carry them be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ſome Juſtice of the peace of the County where they are taken, to find ſureties for the Peace.</p>
               <p>And if they fly into a Franchiſe only within the ſame County where the Affray was, the Conſtable (ſeeing this) may freſhly purſue them and take them out thence.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 8. f. 34. 38 H. 8. Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Affray is over, the Conſtable cannot arreſt the Affrayers without a Warrant. Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept ſome perſon hath received ſuch hurt there that he is in danger of death; but be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Affray begun, and at the time thereof he may arreſt them without a Warrant.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalton,</hi> ibid. It is not properly an Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fray unleſs ſome blow be given or offered to be given; for hot Words is no Affray, nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther can the Conſtable apprehend them for words, unleſs they threaten to kill, beat, or hurt one another, in ſuch caſe the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble may take ſuch perſons and carry them before a Juſtice, to find ſureties for the Peace, and yet ſuch Threatning is no Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fray.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> ch. 8. fo. 35. 5 <hi>H.</hi> 7.6. If an Affray or an Aſſault be made upon the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:109137:29"/>himſelf, he may not only defend him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, but may alſo put the parties offending in the ſtocks, till ſuch time as he can carry them to a Juſtice of the peace, or to the Gaol; and if he be not able to Arreſt them himſelf, he may call others to his aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtance, who may juſtifie to Arreſt the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendors.</p>
               <p>27 <hi>R.</hi> 2. ch. 8. Sheriffs, Conſtables, and all other the Kings officers, ſhall ſuppreſs Riots, and Impriſon them, and all other of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendors againſt the Peace.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Lambert,</hi> 179, 181. <hi>Bro.</hi> tit. Riot, 4, 5. <hi>Co.</hi> 3 part Inſtit. fol. 176. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 85. fol. 217. Where three perſons or more ſhall come and Aſſemble themſelves toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, to the intent to do any Unlawful act with force or violence againſt the perſon of another, his poſſeſſions or goods, as to kill, beat, or otherwiſe to hurt, or to impriſon a a man; to pull down a houſe, wall, pale, hedge, or ditch; wrongfully to enter upon or into another mans poſſeſſion, houſe, or lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or wrongfully to cut or take away corn, graſs, wood, or other goods; or to hunt unlawfully in any Park or Warren, or to do any other unlawful act, (with force or vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence) againſt the peace, or to the manifeſt terrour of the people; if they only meet to
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:109137:29"/>ſuch a purpoſe or intent, although they ſhall after depart of their own accord, without acting any thing, yet this is an unlawful Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembly, becauſe of their intention at firſt.</p>
               <p>And if after ſuch meeting they ſhall ride, move or go forward, towards the execution of ſuch Act, whether they put their intended purpoſe in execution or not, this is a Rout. And if they do act any ſuch thing indeed, then it is a Riot.</p>
               <p n="2">2. <hi>Armes, Militia.</hi> 2 <hi>E.</hi> 3. ch. 3.7 <hi>R.</hi> 2.13. <hi>Co.</hi> 3 part Inſtitutes, fol. 162. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 9. f. 35. &amp; 159. If any perſon ſhall ride or go Armed offenſively before the Kings Juſtices, or before any other the Kings officers or miniſters during their office, or in Fairs, or Markets, or elſewhere by night or by day, in Affray of the Kings people and breach of the peace; or wear or carry any Guns, Daggers, or Piſtols charged, in ſuch caſe the Conſtable upon ſight hereof may ſeize and take away their Armour and other Weapons, and cauſe them to be apprized, and anſwered to the King as forfeited; and carry the parties before a Juſtice of peace to find Sureties for the peace.</p>
               <p>2 <hi>E.</hi> 3. ch. 3. But the Kings ſervants in His preſence, Sheriffs and their officers, and other the Kings miniſters, and ſuch as
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:109137:30"/>be in their companies aſſiſting them in their office, and all others purſuing Hue and Cry where any Felony or other offences againſt the peace be committed, may lawfully bear Armour or Weapons.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. chap. 3. All High-Conſtables, Petty-Conſtables and other officers, within their ſeveral Pariſhes, are to be ayding and aſſiſting to ſuch perſons as ſhall have War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants from the Lord Lievtenants or any two of their Deputies, under their hands and ſeals, to ſearch for and ſeize all Armes in the cuſtody and poſſeſſion of any perſon or perſons whom the ſaid Lievtenants or their Deputies ſhall judge to be dangerous to the peace of the Kingdom, and to ſecure the ſame, and give account thereof to the ſaid Officers; but ſuch ſearch is to be made in the day time only, between Sun-riſe and Sun-ſet, and not otherwiſe; unleſs it be in Cities and their ſuburbs, Towns-corporate and Market-towns, or Houſes within the Bills of mortality; in which places ſearch may be in the night, if the Warrant ſo direct.</p>
               <p>No dwelling-houſe of any Peer of the Realm is to be ſearched, unleſs the Warrant be from the Kings Majeſty, under his <hi>Sign manual;</hi> or in the preſence of the Lievte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant,
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:109137:30"/>or one of the Deputy-Lievtenants of the ſaid County or Riding: And in all places and houſes aforeſaid where ſearch is made, in caſe of Reſiſtance to enter with Force; and ſuch Arms ſo ſeized, where the Lievtenants or their Deputies, or any two of them think fit, may be reſtored to the owners again.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. cap. 3. &amp; 15. <hi>Car.</hi> 2. cap. 4. The Conſtables by Warrant under the hand and ſeal of the Lord Lievtenant, or any three or more of the Deputy Lievtenants, are to levy ſuch ſumms, forfeitures, penalties, and payments, as ſhall be charged upon any perſon or perſons within their ſeveral Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties, for the furniſhing of Armes, horſe or foot, or payment of Souldiers.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Ibid.</hi> And where ſufficient diſtreſs can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be had, then the Lord-Lievtenants and their Deputies by like warrant to the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable may commit ſuch offendor to priſon, until he ſhall make ſatisfaction, according to the ſaid forfeiture, payment, or penalty.</p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>Eſcapes.</hi> Dalton, J.P. ch. 106. f. 272. <hi>Bro.</hi> coron. 112.224.316.454. &amp; <hi>Bro.</hi> Eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cape, 31. <hi>Stamford,</hi> fo. 32. If a Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble or any other officer which hath a priſoner in cuſtody for Felony or ſuſpition thereof, voluntarily letteth or ſuffereth the priſoner
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:109137:31"/>to go where he will at liberty, (though this be breaking of priſon) yet it is Felony in the Gaoler, Conſtable, or him that letteth ſuch priſoner eſcape, but it is no Felony in the priſoner: but if ſuch a priſoner ſhall eſcape by the negligence of his keeper, and againſt his will and knowledge, then it is Felony in the priſoner, becauſe a breach of Priſon, and the Gaoler or Conſtable, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall be fined by the Judges or Juſtices for ſuch Eſcape.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> cap. 106. fol. 272. If a Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble or other officer ſhall voluntarily ſuffer a Thief, being in his cuſtody, to go into the water and drown himſelf, this eſcape is Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lony in the Conſtable, and the Thief is <hi>Felo de ſe;</hi> but if the Thief ſhall ſuddenly (without the aſſent of the Conſtable) kill, hang, or drown himſelf, this is then but a negligent eſcape in the Conſtable, and fine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> ibid. The voluntary letting a Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lon eſcape before he be arreſted for the Felony, is no Felony in him that ſuffereth him to eſcape; but if the Conſtable ſuffer one to eſcape whom he knows hath committed a Felony, is finable, if it do not make him acceſſary.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Cromp.</hi> 40.44. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 106.
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:109137:31"/>fo. 275. Where a Felony is committed and one is arreſted for the ſame, or ſuſpition thereof, though the Conſtable <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter have certain intelligence and knowledge, that the party arreſted is not guilty of the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence, yet they may not ſet the party at li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty; for he muſt not be delivered but by due courſe of Law.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 118. fo. 340. If a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable convey a Feion to the Gaol, and the Gaoler will not receive him, then the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable muſt bring him back to the Town where he was taken, and that Town ſhall be charged with the keeping of him until the next Gaol-delivery, and in ſuch caſe the Gaoler ſhall be puniſhed by the Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Ibid.</hi> The Conſtable or other officer that ſhall impriſon any Felon in the ſtocks, may lock the ſtocks, and if need be, may alſo put Irons on the priſoner; and when he con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyeth him to the Gaol, or to the Juſtice, he may pinion him, or otherwiſe make him ſure ſo that he cannot eſcape.</p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi>Forcible Entries.</hi> 15 <hi>R.</hi> 2. chap. 2. <hi>Dalt.</hi> ch. 22. f. 57. If a Conſtable, or any other private perſon of the ſame County do refuſe to attend and aſſiſt the Juſtices of the peace, upon requeſt to remove a Force, or to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vey
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:109137:32"/>the parties to the Gaol, he may be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſoned for his neglect, and make Fine to the King.</p>
               <p n="6">6. <hi>The Peace. H.</hi> 7. fo. 18. <hi>A. Cromp.</hi> 6.12. The Conſtable ought to do what he can to keep the Peace, but he cannot take ſurety of the Peace at the requeſt of any man.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> ch. 3.9. The Conſtable or other officer before he arreſt the party upon a War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant for the Peace, ought firſt to acquaint the party therewith, and charge him in the Kings name to go along with him to the Juſtice to put in ſureties, according to the Warrant; and if the party refuſe ſo to do, then the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficer ought forthwith to take and convey him to the Gaol, without carrying him to any Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice at all, there to remain till he doth find Sureties; and then at the next Seſſions of the peace the Officer ought to deliver in his Warrant, and certifie what he hath done therein.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> 69. f. 166. If the party yield to go, and find Sureties, then the Officer may not abſolutely arreſt him, yet he is not bound to go up and down with him till he can get Sureties, but he may keep him till he can get Sureties to come unto him; and if the party make reſiſtance, or offer to
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:109137:32"/>go away afterwards, the Officer may carry him to the Gaol, or ſet him in the Stocks till he can get ayd to carry him to the Gaol.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Lambert,</hi> 101. <hi>Dalt</hi> J. P. ch. 69. f. 168. If an officer having a Warrant from a Juſtice of peace againſt a man to find ſureties for the Peace, and do afterwards receive a <hi>Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perſedeas</hi> out of the Chancery, or Kings Bench, or from another Juſtice of peace of the ſame County to diſcharge the ſame Surety of the peace; and yet nevertheleſs the Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer will cauſe the party to find ſureties by virtue of the Warrant, the party may refuſe to give it; and if he be arreſted or impri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoned for ſuch refuſal, he may have his Action of <hi>Falſe impriſonment</hi> againſt ſuch Officer; for the <hi>Superſedeas</hi> is a diſcharge of the former Warrant.</p>
               <p>13 <hi>H.</hi> 7.10. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 75. f. 189. I. a Conſtable be informed, that a man and woman be in Adultery or Fornication toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, or, that a man and woman of evil re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port are gone to a ſuſpected houſe together in the night, the Conſtable may take com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany with him, and if he find them ſo, he may carry them before a Juſtice of the peace to find Sureties for their good beha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viour.</p>
               <pb n="52" facs="tcp:109137:33"/>
               <p> 
                  <hi>Fitz. Barr.</hi> 207. <hi>Cromp.</hi> 135. If any ſhall abuſe a Conſtable in the execution of his office, the Conſtable may have him bound to his good behaviour for it.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> ch. 3. f. 9. Any injurious force or violence uſed againſt the perſon of another, his goods, lands, or other poſſeſſions, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther it be by threatning words, or furious ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtures, or force of the body, or any other force uſed <hi>in Terrorem,</hi> is ſaid to be a breach of the Peace.</p>
               <p n="6">6. <hi>Hedge-breakers, Roblers of Orchards,</hi> &amp;c. 43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 7. Such as are convicted before a Juſtice of the peace, for cutting and taking away of Corn growing, robbing of Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chards, breaking Hedges, and their procu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers and receivers knowing the ſame, are to give the party grieved ſuch ſatisfaction as a Juſtice of peace ſhall think fit; and if they cannot give ſuch ſatisfaction, then the Juſtice may commit the offendors to the Conſtable to be whipped for the firſt offence, and the like pain for the ſecond offence; and if the Conſtable or other officer do not by himſelf or ſome other ſee the ſame done accordingly, then the Juſtice may commit ſuch officer to the Gaol, there to remain without Bayl until he procure the offendor to be whipped as aforeſaid.</p>
               <pb n="53" facs="tcp:109137:33"/>
               <p> 15 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 2. The Conſtables, Head<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boroughs or other perſon, in every County, City, Town-corporate or other place where they ſhall be officers and inhabitants, have power to apprehend or cauſe to be apprehen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded ſuch perſons as they ſuſpect, for having, carrying or conveying any burthen, or bundles of any kind of Wood, Underwood, Poles, or young Trees, or Bark of any trees, or Gates, Stiles, Poſts, Rayls, Pales, Hedge-wood, Broom, or Furze; and any Conſtable or Headborough, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by warrant under the hand and ſeal of one Juſtice, may enter into the houſes, out-houſes, yards, gardens, or other places belonging to the houſes of ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons as they ſhall ſuſpect, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and where they ſhall find any, to apprehend the parties ſuſpected for cutting the ſame, and thoſe in whoſe cuſtody, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> any ſuch Wood or Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derwood ſhall be found, and carry them be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore a Juſtice of the peace, and if the party cannot give a good account to the Juſtice how he came by the ſaid Wood, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by the conſent of the Owner, or ſhall not, within the time the Juſtice ſhall appoint, prove who he bought it of, then ſuch perſon ſhall be deemed convicted of the cutting and ſpoyl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of Wood, within the Statute of 43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> and for the firſt offence ſhall give ſuch
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:109137:34"/>ſatisfaction to the owner within ſuch time as the Juſtice ſhall appoint, and pay over and above preſently to the uſe of the Poor where the offence is committed, ſo much money as the Juſtice ſhall appoint, not exceeding Ten ſhillings: And for default of performance hereof, the Juſtice may commit the offendor to the houſe of Correction ſo long time as he ſhall think fit, not exceeding one Month; or otherwiſe to be whipped by the Conſtable or other officer: And for the ſecond offence the offendor is to be ſent to the houſe of Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection for one Month, and there held to hard labour; and if he be convicted the third time, then to be puniſhed as an incorrigible Rogue.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. ibid.</hi> If any perſon buy any bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thens of Wood, Underwood, Sticks, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of any who may juſtly be ſuſpected to have come by the ſame unlawfully, upon com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint to a Juſtice, Head-officer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and if upon examination upon Oath it appears, That the ſame were bought of ſuch perſon as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, the Juſtice may order the buyer to pay the treble value thereof to him from whom they were ſtollen; and for non-payment the Juſtice may grant his Warrant to the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, to levy the ſame by diſtreſs and ſale of the offendors goods, rendring to the owner
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:109137:34"/>the overplus; and for want of ſuch diſtreſs, then to commit the party to the Gaol, at his own charge, there to remain one Month without bayl.</p>
               <p>None is to be puniſhed by this <hi>Statute,</hi> that hath been puniſhed for any former Law for the ſame offence, and all offendors with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in this <hi>Statute</hi> muſt be proſecuted within ſix Weeks after the offence committed.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Setting-dogs.</hi> Stat. 7. <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 11. <hi>Dal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton,</hi> J. P. ch. 37. fol. 90. The Conſtable, Tythingman, or Headborough of any place (upon a Warrant under the hands and ſeals of two or more Juſtices of the Peace) hath power to ſearch the Houſes of any perſons ſuſpected to keep <hi>Setting-dogs,</hi> or <hi>Nets,</hi> for the taking of Pheaſants or Partridges, and the <hi>Dogs</hi> and <hi>Nets</hi> there found, to take, car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry away, detain, kill, deſtroy, and cut in pieces.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> Dalt. <hi>ibid.</hi> But they cannot ſearch the houſes of any who have free War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ren, or any Lords of any Manor, or ſuch as have 40. Pounds <hi>per ann.</hi> or more in Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold, or ſome Eſtate of Inheritance, or 80. Pounds <hi>per annum</hi> for Life, or be worth in perſonal Eſtate 400. Pounds; Theſe may keep <hi>Nets</hi> and <hi>Dogs,</hi> to take Pheaſants or Partridges in their own ground.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="7" type="chapter">
               <pb n="56" facs="tcp:109137:35"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. VII.</hi> The Conſtables office touching Clothiers, Maultſlers, Alehouſes, Drunkenneſs, Weights and Meaſures, Purvey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ances, High-ways.</head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>CLothiers.</hi> 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 5. Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles and other officers upon requeſt, are to ayd and aſſiſt the Wardens and Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtants, for regulating the Trade of <hi>Worſteds</hi> and other Stuffs called <hi>Norwich</hi>-Stuffs, made in <hi>Norwich</hi> and the County of <hi>Nor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wich.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>They ought to be very vigilant in this buſineſs, for there never was ſuch ſlight and unſerviceable Stuffs made as now are; to the great damage of his Majeſties ſubjects.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 5. In the Weſt-riding of the County of <hi>York,</hi> the Conſtables are like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe by warrant from the Juſtices of the peace, Maſters and Wardens of the Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration, or any thirteen of them, to levy ſuch Fines, Penalties and Forfeitures as ſhall grow due from any <hi>Clothier</hi> by virtue of the Statute aboveſaid, by diſtreſs and ſale of the
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:109137:35"/>offendors goods, rendring the overplus to the owner upon demand.</p>
               <p>4 <hi>E.</hi> 3. ch. 1. <hi>Fitz.</hi> J. P. 103. <hi>Clothiers</hi> muſt pay their Spinners and other work-folks their Wages in ready Money, and not in Wares; and ſhall deliver their Wool in due weight, on pain to forfeit Six pence for every default. And the Carders, Spinners, Weavers, and other work-folks are to do their work faithfully on pain to forfeit double damages to the party grieved.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> The Maſter, or Head-officer in a Corporation where there is no Maſter, and out of a Corporation, every Juſtice of peace, High-Conſtable, and Stewards of Court-Leets ſhall hear and determine the complaints, as well for non-payment of the Work-folks wages, as the damages afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid (by examining the parties,) for which damages they have power to commit the offendors to the Gaol until the party grieved be ſatisfied.</p>
               <p>39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 20. The Juſtices of peace and High-Conſtables may ſearch any houſe or other place for <hi>Tenters, Ropes, Rings, Head-wrinches,</hi> or other Engines for ſtretch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of Cloth, and if they find any to deface them; and if the Owners uſe them again, theſe Officers may take them away and
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:109137:36"/>ſell them, and give the money to the Poor.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Mault-making.</hi> 2 <hi>E.</hi> 6. ch. 10.21 <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 28. 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. ch. 4. The Conſtables and Bayliffs of any Town ought from time to time to view and ſearch all ſuch <hi>Mault</hi> as ſhall be made, or put to ſale within any of their Liberties, and if they find any being evil made, or mingled with evil Mault, then the Conſtable or Bayliff, with advice of one Juſtice of peace, may fell the ſame to ſuch perſons at ſuch a rate as the Juſtice ſhall think ſitting.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat.</hi> 2. E. 6. ch. 10. There are three ſorts of evil and deceitful <hi>Mault,</hi> viz.</p>
               <list>
                  <item>1. Where Barley and Mault hath not in the making thereof, in the Fatt, Floor, ſteep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and drying thereof, (three Weeks at the leaſt;) Except it be in <hi>June, July</hi> and <hi>Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guſt,</hi> and in thoſe Months it muſt have 17. Dayes: and under ſuch time it cannot be made wholeſome.</item>
                  <item>2. They ought to take out of every Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of Mault half a peck or more of Duſt, by treading, rubbing and fanning the ſame, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they put the ſame to ſale, or elſe they forfeit 20. Pence for every Quarter other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe ſold, to be divided between the King and the Informer.</item>
                  <pb n="59" facs="tcp:109137:36"/>
                  <item>3. If any Mault ſhall be put to ſale not well made, according to the limited time, or made of mow-burnt or ſpired Barley, or mixed good and bad together, they forfeit Two ſhillings for every Quarter, to be divi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded as aforeſaid.</item>
               </list>
               <p>This Act extends not to ſuch as make <hi>Mault</hi> for their own proviſion only; and the Forfeitures aforeſaid muſt be proſecuted within one Year.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Alehouſes. Drunkenneſs.</hi> 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. ch. 3. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J.P. ch. 7. fol. 31, 32. If any one keepr an Alehouſe, or ſell Beer or Ale with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Licenſe, he forfeits 20. Shillings to the uſe of the Poor; to be levied by diſtreſs and ſale of the offendors goods, by the Conſtable and Churchwardens by warrant from a Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice of peace before whom the offence is proved; which Goods are to be ſold with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in three dayes after the Diſtreſs taken, and the overplus to be returned, if any be: And in default of Diſtreſs, the delinquent is to be openly Whipped by the Conſtable; If the Conſtable refuſe or neglect to execute his Warrant, he forfeits 40. Shillings to the Poor; and the Juſtice may commit the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable to the Gaol, until he cauſeth the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendor to be whipped, or payeth the 40. Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings to the uſe of the Poor.</p>
               <pb n="60" facs="tcp:109137:37"/>
               <p> 
                  <hi>Co.</hi> 9. lib. Rep. fol. 87. b. 10 <hi>H.</hi> 7.8. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 7. f. 28. If a common Inn-keeper or Alehouſe-keeper refuſeth to lodge a Travelle, he proffering to pay ready money for his victuals, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the Conſtable may cauſe ſuch an Inn-keeper or Alehouſe-keeper to be indicted at the Seſſions or Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſizes, where he may be fined and impriſoned; or the party grieved may have his Action of the Caſe againſt the Inn-keeper or Alehouſe-keeper. But they are not bound to lodge, or find victuals without ready money firſt paid, if it be required.</p>
               <p>In the Condition of the Recognizance, which every Alehouſe-keeper enters into that is licenſed to ſell drink, it is one Clauſe, That he ſhall keep one or more ſpare Beds for lodging of ſtrangers. <hi>Were this well looked into in and about</hi> London, <hi>abundance of forfeited Recognizances would be found; and a great many lazy knaves that live at their eaſe by ſelling Drink, might be ſet to work for their livings.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>They are bound likewiſe not to ſuffer any Gaming in their houſes or backſides, which now is the main prop of moſt of them; and there they draw in Apprentices and Servants to their ruin: were they puniſhed according to the Statute for this, theſe
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:109137:37"/>
                  <hi>Caterpillars</hi> would not ſwarm ſo thick as they do.</p>
               <p>1 <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 9. 1 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. ch. 4. If any Inn-keeper, Alehouſe-keeper, or Victualer do ſell leſs than a full Ale-Quart of the beſt Ale or Beer, or two Quarts of the Small for one Penny, he forfeits 20. Shillings for eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry offence. If he ſuffers Townſmen or others to ſit tipling in his houſe, he forfeits 10. Shillings; for which the Conſtables and Churchwardens upon a Warrant from a Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice of peace ought to diſtrein and levy the Forfeitures, according to the Statute; and if there be no diſtreſs to be found, or if the Officers neglect within twenty dayes to cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifie the ſame Default to the Juſtices, the Officers forfeit 40. Shillings to the uſe of the Poor, to be levied by diſtreſs on their Goods by Warrant made to any indifferent perſon, from any one or more Juſtices of the peace under their hand and ſeal: and for want of diſtreſs, the Juſtice may commit the offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dors to the Gaol, there to remain till they have payd the ſaid Forfeitures. In all theſe caſes the Diſtreſſes are to be kept ſix dayes, and if the parties do not pay the Forfeitures within that time, then the Diſtreſs is to be apprized and ſold, and the overplus returned to the owners if any be.</p>
               <pb n="62" facs="tcp:109137:38"/>
               <p> 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 7. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 7. f. 28. If the Conſtable or other officer of the Pariſh neglect to ſerve the Juſtices Warrant againſt Townſmen, or others for tipling in any Inn, Alehouſe, or Victualing-houſe; or againſt men for being drunk, <hi>viz.</hi> for Tipling 3. <abbr>
                     <hi>s.</hi>
                  </abbr> 
                  <hi>4d.</hi> and for being Drunk 5. <abbr>
                     <hi>s.</hi>
                  </abbr> to be levied by diſtreſs on the Offendors goods, and ſale thereof after ſix dayes default of payment, rendring the overplus to the Owner; And for want of diſtreſs, or not able to pay, the Tipler is to ſit in the Stocks four hours, and the Drunkard ſix hours. And if in any of theſe caſes the Conſtable neglect to do his duty, he forfeits Ten ſhillings, to be levied by diſtreſs and ſale of his goods to the uſe of the Poor. Theſe Offences are to be enquired after within Six moneths after they are committed, and the Conſtables and other officers of the Pariſh may be charged upon their Oaths to preſent them.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Weights and Meaſures.</hi> 8 <hi>H.</hi> 6. ch. 5. All Cities, Boroughs, and Market-Towns in <hi>England</hi> ought to keep common Weights and Meaſures ſealed, at which the Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants may weigh freely; and all Foreiners muſt pay for every draught under forty Pounds, one Farthing; for a draught be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween forty and an hundred, an Halſpeny;
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:109137:38"/>and for a draught between an hundred and a thouſand, one Penny; wherewith the Weights are to be maintained: and the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers which attend that ſervice are to be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warded at the diſcretion of the Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants.</p>
               <p>8 <hi>H.</hi> 6. ch. 5. 11 <hi>H.</hi> 7. ch. 4. Every City which wants ſuch Weights and Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſures forfeits ten Pounds to the King, every Borough five Pounds, and every Market-Town forty Shillings: And the chief Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers of ſuch places (upon requeſt to them made) are to Mark and Seal ſuch Weights and Meaſures to any of the Kings ſubjects; taking for the marking of every Buſhel one Penny: and none ought to ſell with any other Weights and Meaſures but ſuch as are marked or ſealed.</p>
               <p>11 <hi>H.</hi> 7. ch. 4. The Mayors, and chief officers in Cities, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are once every year at leaſt to view all Meaſures and Weights in their Juriſdictions, and to break or burn ſuch as they find defective; and to puniſh the offendors for the firſt offence 6. Shillings eight pence, for the ſecond 13. Shillings four pence, and for the third offence 20. Shillings; and beſides may adjudge the offendors to the Pillory.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Purveyance.</hi> 13 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 8. The
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:109137:39"/>Clerk or chief officer of the Kings Carria<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges, ſhall three dayes before His Majeſties arrival, by warrant from the Green-cloth, give notice in writing to two Juſtices of the peace adjoyning to the place where His Majeſty is to come, to provide ſuch a num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of Carts and Carriages as the ſaid Off<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer ſhall need for that work; and to expreſs the time and place where the ſaid Carts and Carriages are to attend, and then theſe Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices are to require the Countrey to provide the number of Carts and carriages of four able Horſes, or four Oxen and two Horſes a piece; at ſix pence a mile for every mile they go laden, to be payd them in hand at the place of Lading; and no Carriage to be enforced to travel above One dayes journey from the place where they receive their lading; and if any refuſe, or ſhall not be ready at the time and place, and having not good cauſe to the contrary, the Juſtices upon proof there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of by two witneſſes, or the oath of the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable or other officer may (by their warrant) cauſe to be levied by diſtreſs and ſale of the offendors goods 40. Shillings.</p>
               <p>13 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. chap. 8. If any Juſtice of peace or officer take any giſt to ſpare any perſon from making ſuch Carriage, or ſhall preſs more Carriages than is directed from
<pb n="65" facs="tcp:109137:39"/>the <hi>Green-cloth,</hi> the offendor forfeits Ten pounds, to be recovered by any perſon by Action of Debt in any Court of Record.</p>
               <p>12 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 24.13 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 8. No pre-emption ſhall be allowed to the King, His heirs or ſucceſſors, nor to the Queen or any of the Children of the Royal Family, in market or out of market; but all ſubjects may diſpoſe of their goods as they pleaſe: And if any perſon ſhall make any Purvey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance, or impreſs any Carriages (otherwiſe than is appointed by 13 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 8. by or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der from the Green-cloth) or other things by colour of any authority of Purveyance for the King, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> contrary to the Act 12 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 24. then two or one Juſtice of the peace next adjoyning, and the Conſtable of the place where ſuch offence is committed, upon complaint of the party grieved may ſend the offendor to the Gaol, until the next Seſſions, there to be indicted for the ſame: And the party grieved may have his Action againſt the offendor, and therein ſhall recover treble Damages and treble Coſts.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 20. Two or more Juſtices of the peace by Warrant from the Lord High-Admiral of <hi>England,</hi> or two or more of the principal Officers, or Commiſſioners
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:109137:40"/>of the Navy, or the Maſter of his Majeſties Ordnance, or the Lieutenant of His Ord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance, are to provide Carriages with horſes and oxen out of the Countrey, not being above twelve miles diſtant from the place of Lading; the owners of which Carriages or their ſervants are to receive Twelve pence a Mile for every Load of Timber, and Eight pence a Mile for every Tun of other com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities. And ſuch perſons as neglect or refuſe to make their appearance, upon oath thereof made before the Juſtices by the Conſtable or two witneſſes, the perſon re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſing or neglecting forfeits Twenty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, to be levied by diſtreſs and ſale of his Goods by warrant from the ſaid Juſtices, Mayor or other chief Officer, or from the principal Officers or Commiſſioners of His Majeſties Navy, or Maſter or Lieutenant of His Majeſties Ordnance; rendring to the owner the overplus if any be, firſt de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ducting the charge of Diſtreining.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. ibid.</hi> No Horſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or Land-carriage ſhall be forced to travel more dayes-journey from the place where they receive their lading, nor be compelled to continue longer in the employment than the ſaid Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices ſhall appoint; and that ready mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney be paid to the parties in hand at
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:109137:40"/>the place of Lading, according to the Rates aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>The Act of 14 <hi>Car.</hi> ch. 20. &amp; 13. cap. 8. are to continue until the end of the firſt Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of the next Parliament.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>High-wayes.</hi> 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 6. The Churchwardens, Conſtables, or Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men of every pariſh, are upon Monday or Tueſday in <hi>Eaſter-week</hi> (after notice given publickly in the Church the Sunday before) after Morning prayer ended, with the advice and conſent of the major part of the Pariſh then preſent, to chuſe two or more ſufficient Inhabitants of the place to be Surveyors for the <hi>High-wayes</hi> for the Year following; and give notice thereof to the parties cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen in writing, under pain of Five pounds.</p>
               <p>This Act is to continue until the end of the firſt Seſſion of the next Parliament.</p>
               <p>2, 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> ch. 8. The Churchwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Conſtables, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> offending herein, may be puniſhed by Fine or Amerciament at the Quarter-Seſſions, by the diſcretion of the Juſtices.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. ibid.</hi> P. <hi>&amp;</hi> M. <hi>&amp;</hi> 5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 13. The Conſtables and Churchwardens are then alſo to appoint ſix dayes between that and the four and twentieth day of <hi>June,</hi> for
<pb n="68" facs="tcp:109137:41"/>the Amendment of the <hi>High-wayes,</hi> and to give publick notice thereof in the Church the next Sunday after.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> Stewards in Leets have power to inquire after the breach of this Statute about <hi>High-wayes,</hi> and to ſet Fines upon ſuch as make default at their diſcretion; and ſhall within ſix weeks after <hi>Michaelmas</hi> deliver indented <hi>Eſtreats</hi> thereof under their hands and ſeals, <hi>viz.</hi> one part to the Bay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liff or High-Conſtable of the Liberty, and the other to the Conſtable and Churchwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens where the default was made.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> In default of preſentment thereof in Leets, the Juſtices of peace may inquire thereof in their Seſſions, and ſet ſuch Fines as they or any two of them (whereof one muſt be of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) ſhall think fit, whereof the Clerk of the peace ſhall deliver indented <hi>Eſtreats</hi> in manner as is aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem. Dalton,</hi> J. P. ch. 76. fol. 71. Theſe <hi>Eſtreats</hi> of Stewards of Leets or Clerk of the peace ſhall be a ſufficient War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant for the Bayliff or chief Conſtable to levy the ſaid Fines by way of diſtreſs; and if no diſtreſs can be found, or the party do not pay the Fine within twenty dayes after de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand thereof, he or they ſhall forfeit double
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:109137:41"/>ſo much; All which Fines and forfeitures ſhall be beſtowed on the High-wayes in the ſame Pariſh, by the Conſtable and Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens there.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem. Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 26. fol. 70. The Bayliff or High-Conſtable is yearly be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the firſt of <hi>March</hi> and laſt of <hi>April,</hi> to render unto the Conſtable and Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens, to whom the other part of the <hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>streat</hi> was delivered, a true Account of the Moneys received by them, in pain of forty Shillings. And the ſaid Conſtables and Churchwardens have power to call the Bay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liff or High-Conſtable before two Juſtices (one of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) to paſs the Account, who have power to commit ſuch Bayliff or High-Conſtable, until they have ſatisfied all the Arrerages by them received.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> Upon paſſing their Account every Bayliff or High-Conſtable ſhall be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed Eight pence for every Pound col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected, and Twelve pence for the fee of the <hi>Eſtreat</hi> delivered.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem. Dalt.</hi> ch. 26. f. 21. Any two Juſtices of peace upon complaint to them made by the ſucceeding Conſtables and Churchwardens may call before them the precedent Conſtables and Churchwardens,
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:109137:42"/>and compel them to pay in all Arrerages in their hands.</p>
               <p>18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 10. The Surveyors by warrant from two Juſtices of the peace, are to levy by diſtreſs and ſale of goods, the Forfeitures of all ſuch perſons as offend in not ſcowring their Ditches, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and if they neglect to levy the Forfeiture for the ſpace of a year after the offence committed, then the Juſtices may ſend to the Conſtable and Churchwardens to levy the ſame.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 2. Conſtables or other officers by warrant from any of His Majeſties Juſtices of either Bench, Barons of the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer, or Juſtices of the peace to them directed, are to levy by diſtreſs and ſale of the offendors goods, all ſuch penalties as ſhall be forfeited by the ſaid Act touching repairing the <hi>High-wayes</hi> and <hi>Sewers,</hi> and for paving and keeping clean the Streets in and about the Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtmin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ster;</hi> and for default of diſtreſs, or non<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>payment of the ſaid Penalties within ſix dayes after demand thereof, or notice in writing left at the houſe or dwelling place of the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendor by the ſaid Conſtable or other officer; the ſaid offendor (not being a Peer of the Realm) may be committed to the common Gaol of the ſaid County or City, by warrant
<pb n="71" facs="tcp:109137:42"/>of any ſuch Juſtice under his hand and ſeal, there to remain without bayl or mainprize until payment thereof be made.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="8" type="chapter">
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. VIII.</hi> The Conſtables office about Forein Bone<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laces, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Chimney-money, Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stoms, Exciſe, Fiſh.</head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>FOrein Bone-laces, &amp;c.</hi> Conſtables upon Warrant to them directed from the Juſtices of peace, or chief officers of Cities and Corporate-Towns, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are to ſearch in their ſeveral Counties, Cities, Towns and Liberties, in the Shops being open Ware-houſes, and dwelling-houſe of ſuch perſon or perſons who ſhall be ſuſpected to have any Forein <hi>Bone-laces, Cut-works, Embroideries, Fringes, Band-ſtrings, But<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tons,</hi> or <hi>Needle-works,</hi> made of Thred, Silk; or any or either of them made in the parts be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yond the Seas, and where they find any ſuch to ſeize the ſame.</p>
               <p n="2">2. <hi>Chimney-money.</hi> 16 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 3. All Juſtices of the peace, chief Magiſtrates, Treaſurers and Under-Treaſurers, Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles,
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:109137:43"/>and other His Majeſties officers, are within their ſeveral Liberties and Juriſdi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions to ayd and aſſiſt His Majeſties offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers appointed for the collecting of the Duty of <hi>Hearth-money.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> The Officers appointed by His Majeſty for the <hi>Chimney-money,</hi> once every year, being accompanied with the Conſtable or Tythingman, Treaſurer or Under-Treaſurer, or other publick officer of the Peace; and in all Pariſhes and places where there are no Conſtables, Tythingmen or other publick officers as aforeſaid, there without any ſuch aſſiſtance may enter in the day time into any dwelling or other Houſe, Edifice, Lodging, and Chambers in any of the Inns of Court or Chancery, Colledges and other Societies, to ſearch and examine whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther there be any more <hi>Fire-hearths</hi> and <hi>Stoves</hi> in the ſame than were formerly Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turned or certified, and what are increaſed or decreaſed ſince the laſt Certificate; And if they find any variance in the Number re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turned, both the Officer and Officers ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by His Majeſty, and the Conſtable or Tythingman, or other Officer aforeſaid are to certifie the ſame under his or their hands to the Clerk of the peace.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> If the party after demand
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:109137:43"/>made by His Majeſties officers, or their de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puties at the houſe, chamber, or place where the duty ſhall grow due, make default or refuſe to pay, by the ſpace of one hour after ſuch demand, then the officer or his deputy, with the aſſiſtance of the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable or Tythingman, or other Officer, may at any time in the day levy the ſaid duty and all the Arrears thereof, by di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs and ſale of the goods of the parties making default, rendring the overplus to the owners; deducting neceſſary charges for taking the diſtreſs: which charges are not to exceed one moiety of the Duty and Arrears.</p>
               <p>16 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. cap. 3. No arrears of <hi>Hearth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>money</hi> are to be diſtreined for, after the ſpace of two years next after ſuch duty becomes due. And if any violence, oppoſition, or injury be done by any perſon or perſons to any of His Majeſties officers or their depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, in the due execution of their office, Oath being made there of before any one Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice of the peace or chief Magiſtrate, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſuch Juſtice or the Magiſtrate, if they think fit, may commit the offendor to the common Gaol, for any time not exceeding one Moneth.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> The Conſtables are to have
<pb n="74" facs="tcp:109137:44"/>two pence in the pound, paid them by the Collector to whom they pay the <hi>Chimney-money,</hi> by them collected; and are to pay nothing to the Collectors for their Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quittances.</p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>Cuſtomes.</hi> 12 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 19. Any perſon having a Warrant from the Lord Treaſurer or any of the Barons of the Exche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer, or chief Magiſtrate of a Port, for the ſearch of Uncuſtomed goods, may with the aſſiſtance of a Sheriff, Juſtice of the peace, or Conſtable, (who are to be aiding and aſſiſting upon requeſt) may enter into any Houſe in the day time where ſuch goods are ſuſpected to be concealed; and in caſe of reſiſtance, may break open ſuch Houſe and ſeize and ſecure ſuch goods.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> No Houſe is to be entred, unleſs it be within one Month after the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence ſuppoſed to be committed; and if the Information whereupon the Houſe ſhall come to be ſearched do prove falſe, the party injured ſhall recover full Coſts and damages againſt the Informer by Action of Treſpaſs.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 11. Such perſons as are authorized by Writ of Aſſiſtance out of the Exchequer, are to take a Conſtable, Head<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>borough or other officer inhabiting near the
<pb n="75" facs="tcp:109137:44"/>place, and in the day time to enter into any houſe, ſhop, cellar, warehouſe, room, or other place; and in caſe of reſiſtance break open the doors, cheſts, trunks, and other package there to ſeize, and from thence to bring any kind of goods or Merchandize whatſoever prohibited and uncuſtomed, and to put and ſecure the ſame in His Majeſties Storehouſe in the Port next to ſuch place where the ſeizure ſhall be made.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Idem.</hi> All Officers belonging to the Admiralty, Chaplains and Commanders of Ships, Forts, Caſtles, and Blockhouſes; and all Juſtices of peace, Mayors, Sheriffs, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables and Headboroughs, and other the Kings officers and ſubjects whatſoever whom it may concern, are to be aiding and aſſiſting to all and every perſon and perſons which are or ſhall be appointed by His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty to manage his Cuſtoms; and if the Officers of the Cuſtoms, or any acting in ayd of them, ſhall be ſued, indicted, proſecuted or moleſted; ſuch perſons, their Heirs, Executors, and Adminiſtrators may plead the general iſſue, and give the ſeveral Acts re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lating to the Cuſtoms, or any of them in evidence.</p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi>Exciſe.</hi> 12 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 23, 24. Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers employed by the Commiſſioners of
<pb n="76" facs="tcp:109137:45"/>Exciſe, are to take the Conſtable with them when they enter by night into any houſe, to Gage their Coppers, Fatts or veſſels; or to take an account of their Liquors made, brewed, or diſtilled in their Houſes.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Idem.</hi> Such perſons as ſhall be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>victed before the Juſtices of peace, or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners of Exciſe, of any offence and for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture within the Acts of Exciſe; the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables by warrant from the Juſtices of peace are to levy the Penalties upon the goods of the offendors by diſtreſs and ſale thereof, (rendring the overplus;) and for want of diſtreſs, they are to convey the offendors to the Gaol, there to remain until ſatisfaction be made.</p>
               <p>And the Conſtables upon warrant are to ſummon Alehouſe-keepers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to appear before the Commiſſioners at ſuch places and times as ſhall be appointed in the War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="9" type="chapter">
               <pb n="77" facs="tcp:109137:45"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. IX.</hi> Concerning diſturbing of Miniſters, Swearing, Recuſants, Conventicles.</head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>Diſturbing of Miniſters.</hi> 1 <hi>Mar.</hi> Seſſ. 3. ch. 3. <hi>Wingate</hi>'s Stat. tit. Sacraments. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 41. fol. 103. If any perſon purpoſely without Authority, diſturb a <hi>Preacher</hi> lawfully Licenſed, in preaching, praying, or adminiſtration of the Sacraments, either by talking, laughing, humming or the like; any Conſtable or Churchwarden of the place ought preſently to apprehend the party, &amp; carry him before a Juſtice of the peace of the ſame County, who may commit him to ſafe cuſtody; and with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in ſix dayes after, with another Juſtice of the peace they may examine the matter: And if they find it true by two Witneſſes, they muſt commit him to the common Gaol, there to remain for three Months, and from thence to the next Quarter-Seſſions; at which upon the parties reconciliation, and entring into ſecurity for one whole Year, he may be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leaſed; (at the diſcretion of the Juſtices)
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:109137:46"/>but if he continue ſtill in his obſtinacy, he muſt continue in Priſon without bayl till he be penitent.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Idem.</hi> He that Reſcues an offendor in this kind, ſhall ſuffer like Impriſonment, and forfeit Five pounds; and the Inhabitants that ſuffer ſuch an offendor to eſcape, being preſented before the Juſtices at their Seſſions of the County or Corporation where the offence was made, do alſo forfeit Five pounds.</p>
               <p n="2">2. <hi>Prophane Swearing.</hi> 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 20. 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. ch. 4. If any perſon ſhall prophanely Curſe or Swear, they forfeit Twelve pence for every time ſo offending; the offence muſt be preſented within Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty dayes, and proved by two Witneſſes, or confeſſion of the party before a Juſtice of peace or Head-officer of a City or Town-corporate, who may thereupon iſſue out their Warrant to the Conſtables, Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens and Overſeers of the poor of the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh where the offence was committed, to levy the Forfeitures by diſtreſs and ſale of the offendors Goods, rendring the overplus to the owner, if any be.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Idem.</hi> Where no Diſtreſs can be found, the offendor (if above Twelve years of age) ſhall by warrant from a Juſtice, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> be ſet
<pb n="79" facs="tcp:109137:46"/>in the Stocks three whole Hours. But if the offendor be under Twelve years of age, and do not forthwith pay the forfeiture of Twelve pence <hi>per</hi> Oath, then muſt ſuch offendor be whipped by the Conſtable, or by the Parent or Maſter in the preſence of the Conſtable.</p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>Recuſants.</hi> 3 <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 4. The Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables and Churchwardens of every Pariſh or one of them, or High-Conſtable of the Hundred are once a year to preſent at the Seſſions of the Peace, the Monthly abſence from the Church of all <hi>Recuſants</hi> and their Children above Nine years old, and their Servants; on pain to forfeit for every ſuch default reſpectively Twenty ſhillings: which Preſentment the Clerk of the Peace or Town-Clerk is to Enroll without fee, on pain of Forty ſhillings.</p>
               <p>7 <hi>Jac.</hi> 6. If the Miniſter, Churchwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens or Conſtable of any pariſh, or any two of them ſhall complain to any Juſtice of the peace, of any perſon ſuſpected for Recu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſancy, then any ſuch Juſtice may tender the Oath of <hi>Supremacy</hi> to the perſon ſuſpected; and if he refuſe to take it, the Juſtice may commit the party to the Gaol, there to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main until the next Aſſizes or Seſſions of the Peace: And then if the party refuſe again,
<pb n="80" facs="tcp:109137:47"/>he is in <hi>Praemunire;</hi> but if it be a Feme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covert ſhe ſhall only be impriſoned, there to remain without Bayl until ſhe will take the ſaid Oath.</p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi>Conventicles.</hi> 16 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 4. If any Conſtable, Headborough, or Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man neglect to execute the Warrants to them directed for Sequeſtring, diſtraining, and ſelling the Eſtate or goods of any ſedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tious <hi>Conventicler</hi> to be tranſported; or neglect to diſtrain and ſell the goods and chattels of ſuch offendor for the levying of ſuch ſumms of money as ſhall be impoſed upon them for the firſt and ſecond offence; in ſuch caſes the officer ſo offending for his neglect ſhall forfeit Five pounds, the one moiety to the King, the other moiety to him that will ſue for the ſame in any of His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Courts of Record.</p>
               <p>16 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. cap. 4. If any perſon be at any time ſued for putting in execution any of the powers in the Act againſt ſeditious Conventicles, ſuch perſon ſhall and may plead the general iſſue, and give the ſpecial matter in evidence; and if the Plaintiff be nonſuit, or a verdict paſs for the Defendant, or if the Plaintiff diſcontinue his Action, or if upon demurrer Judgement be gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven for the Defendant, every ſuch De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant
<pb n="81" facs="tcp:109137:47"/>ſhall have his or their treble Coſts.</p>
               <p>22 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. If any perſon of the age of Sixteen years and upwards, being a ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject of this Realm, after the Tenth of <hi>May</hi> 1670. ſhall be preſent at any Aſſembly, Conventicle or Meeting, under colour of Religion, in other manner than according to the Liturgy of the Church of <hi>England</hi> in <hi>England, Wales,</hi> or <hi>Berwick</hi> upon <hi>Tweed:</hi> at which Conventicle there ſhall be Five perſons or more over and beſides thoſe of the ſame Houſhold, if in a houſe where a Family is reſiding, or if in a Houſe, Field or place where no Family inhabits, then where Five perſons or more are ſo Aſſembled, one or more Juſtices of the peace of the County, limit or diviſion, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or the Chief Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrate of the place where the offence is com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted, are required upon proof to him or them made by Confeſſion of the party, or Oath of two Witneſſes, or by notorious evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence and circumſtance of the fact, to make a Record of every ſuch offence; And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon the ſaid Juſtice, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall impoſe upon every ſuch offendor ſo convict, a fine of Five ſhillings for ſuch offence, which Record to be certified to the next Quarter-Seſsions of the peace.</p>
               <p n="2">
                  <pb n="82" facs="tcp:109137:48"/> 2. And if the ſaid perſon ſo convicted ſhall again commit the like offence, he ſhall for every ſuch offence incurr the penalty of Ten ſhillings, the ſaid fines to be levied by diſtreſs and ſale of the offendors goods and chattels, and in caſe of poverty, on the goods and chattels of any perſons then con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>victed for the ſame offence at the ſame Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venticle, at the diſcretion of the Juſtices, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſo as the ſumm to be levied upon one in caſe of poverty, of others exceed not Ten pounds upon occaſion of one Meeting. And every Conſtable, Headborough, Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, Churchwardens and Overſeers of the poor, are required to levy the ſame accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly, having firſt a Warrant, and forthwith to deliver the ſaid moneys to the Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of which one Third to be to the King, another Third to the Poor of the pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh where the offence was committed, and the other Third to the Informers and ſuch perſons as ſhall be diligent in the diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very, diſperſing and puniſhing of the ſaid Conventicles.</p>
               <p n="3">3. Every perſon that ſhall take upon him to Teach or Preach in any ſuch Meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and ſhall be convicted as aforeſaid, ſhall forfeit for the firſt offence Twenty pounds, to be levied as aforeſaid: And if
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:109137:48"/>he be a ſtranger, and his name and habita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion not known, or is fled and cannot be found, or in the judgement of the Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall be thought unable to pay the ſame, the ſaid Juſtices, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are required to levy the ſame by warrant upon the goods and chattels of any perſon preſent at the ſame Conventicle, the money ſo levied to be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed as aforeſaid; and for the ſecond offence ſhall incurr the penalty of Forty pounds, to be levied and diſpoſed as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p n="4">4. Every perſon that ſhall ſuffer any ſuch Conventicle or Meeting, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to be held in his or her Houſe, Out-houſe, Barn, Yard, or Backſide, and convicted thereof, ſhall forfeit Twenty pounds, to be levied as aforeſaid; and in caſe of his or her Poverty, upon the goods of any convicted of being preſent at the ſame Conventicle.</p>
               <p n="5">5. Provided no perſon ſhall pay above Ten pounds in any one Meeting, in regard of the Poverty of any other.</p>
               <p n="6">6. Any offendor aggrieved, may within one week after the penalty paid or levied, appeal in writing to the next Quarter-Seſsions, to whom the Juſtices, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> that convicted the offendor, are to return the money, and certifie the evidence upon which the conviction paſt, whereupon ſuch offendor
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:109137:49"/>may plead and have his Tryal by a Jury. And if ſuch Appellant ſhall not be acquitted, he ſhall pay treble Coſts; and no Court but the Quarter-Seſsions ſhall meddle with Cauſes of Appeal upon this Act.</p>
               <p n="7">7. Upon the delivery of ſuch Appeal, the Appellant ſhall enter into a Recognizance to proſecute with effect, or elſe the Appeal to be void.</p>
               <p n="8">8. The Juſtice, Juſtices of the peace, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or the Conſtables by warrant, may with what ayd or force they ſhall think fit, after re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſal, break open and enter into any houſe or place where ſuch Conventicle ſhall be held, and take into cuſtody the perſons there un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawfully Aſſembled; and the Lieutenants, Deputy-Lieutenants, or any Commiſsioned Officer of the Militia or other His Majeſties Forces with horſe and foot, and alſo the She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riffs and other Magiſtrates and Miniſters of Juſtice upon Certificate to them made of ſuch unlawful meeting, are required to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pair to the place where they are ſo held, and diſſolve or prevent the ſame, and take into their cuſtody ſuch perſons ſo aſſembled as they ſhall think meet.</p>
               <p n="9">9. The dwelling-houſe of a Peer, where his Wife is reſident ſhall not be ſearched, but by immediate Warrant from the King, or in
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:109137:49"/>the preſence of the Lieutenant, Deputy-Lieutenant, or Two Juſtices, of which one of the <hi>Quorum.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="10">10. If any Conſtable, Headborough, Ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thingman, Churchwarden, or Overſeer of the Poor ſhall know or be informed of any ſuch Meetings or Conventicles within his precincts, pariſh, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and ſhall not inform ſome Juſtice of peace or chief Magiſtrate, but omit the performance of his duty in the execution of this Act, and thereof be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>victed, ſhall forfeit Five pounds; and every Juſtice of peace or chief Magiſtrate ſo of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fending ſhall forfeit an Hundred pounds, the one moiety to the Informer.</p>
               <p n="11">11. If any perſon be ſued for putting this Act in execution, otherwiſe than by Appeal as aforeſaid, he may plead the general Iſſue, and upon a Nonſuit or Verdict paſt for him, recover treble Coſts.</p>
               <p n="12">12. This Act and all clauſes therein ſhall be conſtrued moſt largely and beneficially for the ſuppreſſing of Conventicles, and juſtification of all perſons employed in the execution of this Act.</p>
               <p n="13">13. Provided every offence againſt this Act muſt be proſecuted within three Moneths, and no perſon puniſhed by this ſhall be puniſhed by any other Law.</p>
               <p n="14">
                  <pb n="86" facs="tcp:109137:50"/> 14. Aldermen of <hi>London</hi> have the ſame power as Juſtices, and lyable to the ſame penalties for neglect of their duties.</p>
               <p n="15">15. A Feme-Covert offending, and co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habiting with her Husband, the penalties of Five and Ten ſhillings ſhall be levied upon the goods of the Husband.</p>
               <p n="16">16. No Peer ſhall be attached, or im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſoned by virtue or force of this Act.</p>
               <p n="17">17. This Act ſhall not invalidate His Majeſties <hi>Supremacy</hi> in Eccleſiaſtical affairs.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="10" type="chapter">
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. X.</hi> The Churchwardens Office.</head>
               <p>THe antiquity of the Office of a <hi>Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warden,</hi> when firſt they received that title is very uncertain; but ſo Ancient it is, that ſome are of opinion, that 87. years after <hi>Britain</hi> had received the Chriſtian Faith, which moſt Hiſtorians do agree was planted here in the Reign of King <hi>Lucius,</hi> in the year of CHRIST 180. who is hitherto ſtiled the firſt Chriſtian King of this Iſle; and that <hi>Dionyſius</hi> in the year 267. did divide both in <hi>Rome</hi> and other places to Biſhops their <hi>Dioceſſes,</hi> and <hi>Pariſhes, Churches</hi> and
<pb n="87" facs="tcp:109137:50"/>
                  <hi>Churchyards</hi> to Prieſts, Vicars and Curates; but whether at that time, or how long after <hi>Churchwardens</hi> were inſtituted, is not cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainly known.</p>
               <p>But all Authors do agree that they are very antient Officers, and M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. <hi>Lambert</hi> ſaith in this <hi>Duty of Churchwardens,</hi> pag. 46. That theſe <hi>Churchwardens</hi> of Pariſhes are at the Common Law taken in the manner of a Corporation, 12 <hi>H.</hi> 7. ult. that is to ſay, <hi>Churchwardens</hi> at the Common Law are per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons enabled by that name, to take moveable goods or chattels, and to ſue or be ſued at the Law concerning ſuch goods for the uſe and profit of their Pariſh.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Lib. Intrat.</hi> fol. 576. A man may in his life time give, or in his laſt Will bequeath, money or other moveable things to the Churchwardens or Pariſhioners, either for the repairing of their Pariſh-Church, or for the buying of Books, Communion-Cups, or linen Clothes, or other decent Ornaments or Furniture for the Church; and it is not needful in ſuch a Gift for a man to uſe ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſs words or writing.</p>
               <p>11 <hi>H.</hi> 4.12. 8 <hi>H.</hi> 7.12. If a man buy a Bell and hang it up in the Steeple, or do make a Pew and ſet it up in the Church, and do neither make any word or writing thereof,
<pb n="88" facs="tcp:109137:51"/>yet by this is the Bell or Pew dedicated or given to the Church.</p>
               <p>37 <hi>H.</hi> 6.30, &amp; 34. 11 <hi>H.</hi> 4.12. The Churchwardens have no Action at the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Law to recover a Legacy, nor any thing which they never had; but if any goods or ornaments of the Church be once in their poſſeſsion and cuſtody, they may maintain an Appeal of Robbery againſt him that ſtealeth them, and an Action of Treſpaſs againſt him that ſhall wrongfully take them away, although it be the Vicar or Parſon himſelf; and the damages that ſhall be recovered thereby ſhall be to the uſe of the Pariſh, and not to their own uſe.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Fitz.</hi> Nat. Br. 91. K. But if thoſe Churchwardens (from whom the Goods were ſo taken) ſhall happen to dye before any Action by them brought for the Goods, the ſucceeding Churchwardens ſhall have an Action for the ſame Goods.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Canon. Eccleſiaſtic.</hi> 89, 90. In the Book of <hi>Conſtitutions</hi> and <hi>Canons Eccleſiaſtical,</hi> agreed upon in the Synod begun at <hi>London anno Dom.</hi> 1603. and in the firſt year of King <hi>James,</hi> it is appointed that Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens, Queſt-men, Side-men, or Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtants in every Pariſh, ſhall be choſen by the joynt-conſent of the Miniſter and the
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:109137:51"/>Pariſhioners if it may be; but if they cannot agree upon ſuch a Choice, then the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter ſhall chooſe one, and the Pariſhioners another: and without ſuch a joynt or ſeveral Choice none ſhall take upon them to be Churchwardens; neither ſhall they continue any longer than one Year in that Office, except they be choſen again in like man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner: and they are to be yearly Choſen in <hi>Eaſter-week.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>But notwithſtanding this <hi>Canon,</hi> where there is an antient Cuſtom in any Pariſh for the choyce of Church vardens contrary to the <hi>Canon,</hi> in ſuch caſe the Cuſtom is to be ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved before the <hi>Canon;</hi> as ſhall be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanced in ſeveral Caſes. <hi>viz.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>The Pariſhioner Caſe of</hi> Rovenden <hi>in</hi> Kent. Rolls <hi>Caſes, part</hi> 2. <hi>fo.</hi> 287. <hi>P.</hi> 5 Jac. <hi>B.R.</hi> If the pariſhioners of a Pariſh have uſed time out of mind, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to chooſe one Churchwarden, and the Parſon or Vicar another, and afterwards a <hi>Canon</hi> is made, that the Vicar ſhall elect two, and he do ſo accordingly; and the Pariſhioners elect one, according to their cuſtom, and the Ordinary diſallows him, and confirms the other two choſen by the Vicar, in this caſe a Prohibition ſhall be granted.</p>
               <p>Tr. 7 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. B. R. <hi>betw.</hi> Shirley <hi>and</hi>
                  <pb n="90" facs="tcp:109137:52"/>Brown, <hi>Rot.</hi> 1391. Rolls 2 <hi>part, fol.</hi> 287. A Prohibition was granted againſt a Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warden choſen by the Parſon of S<hi rend="sup">t</hi>. <hi>Magnus</hi> by <hi>London</hi>-Bridge by force of a <hi>Canon,</hi> upon a ſurmiſe that the Pariſh had a cuſtom to chooſe two Churchwardens.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Warner</hi>'s Caſe, <hi>B. R. P.</hi> 17 <hi>Jac.</hi> The like was granted againſt a Churchwarden choſen by the Parſon of S<hi rend="sup">t</hi>. <hi>Alhallows, London.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>P. 5 <hi>Jac. Cro.</hi> 2. part Rep. <hi>The Caſe of the Pariſhioners of</hi> Walbrook, London.</p>
               <p>P. 15 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. <hi>B. R.</hi> The like againſt a Churchwarden choſen by the Parſon of S<hi rend="sup">t</hi>. <hi>Thomas</hi> in <hi>London, Cro.</hi> 3. part, <hi>Evelyn</hi>'s Caſe.</p>
               <p>Paſc. 4. ca. 1. B. R. rot. 420. <hi>Rolls</hi> Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, 2. part, fo. 287. The like granted be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween <hi>Draper</hi> and <hi>Stone,</hi> for <hi>Abchurch</hi> in <hi>London.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>An Attorney cannot be made a Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warden; but if he be put in, and refuſe, and be ſued in the Spiritual Court, he may have a Prohibition. <hi>Wilſon</hi>'s Caſe, P. 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. B. R. and <hi>Baker</hi>'s Caſe, Tr. 15 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. B.R. <hi>Rolls</hi> Caſes, 2. part, ſo. 272.</p>
               <p>15 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. cap. 5. All <hi>Veſtrey-men</hi> or members of any Veſtrey within any pariſh in <hi>London, Weſtminſter,</hi> Borough of <hi>South<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wark,</hi> and Bills of Mortality; and in all
<pb n="91" facs="tcp:109137:52"/>other Cities, Boroughs, and Towns-corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate in <hi>England,</hi> where ſelect Veſtries are uſed, are within one Moneth after their Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, before the reſpective Archbiſhop, Biſhop, Ordinary, Vicar-general, or Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellor of the Dioceſs, to make and ſubſcribe as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="declaration">
                  <body>
                     <p>
                        <hi>I A. B.</hi> do declare, That it is not lawful upon any pretence whatſoever, to take up Armes againſt His Majeſty, and that I do abhor that Trayterous poſition of taking Arms by His Majesties authority against His Perſon, or againſt thoſe that are Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſionated by him: And that I will Conform to the Liturgy of <hi>England,</hi> as it is now eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhed: And I do declare, That I hold there lies no obligation on me, or on any other perſon, from the Oath commonly called, <hi>The Solemn League and Covenant,</hi> to endeavour any change or alteration of Government either in Church or State: And that the ſame was in it ſelf an unlawful <hi>Oath,</hi> and impoſed upon the ſubjects of this Realm againſt the known Laws and Liberties of this Kingdom.</p>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <pb n="92" facs="tcp:109137:53"/>
               <p> 
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> He that refuſes to make this Subſcription within the ſaid time, is <hi>ipſo facto</hi> deprived of his place of Veſtry-man, and a new one is to be choſen in his ſtead; and if ſuch new one alſo refuſe to ſubſcribe, or if ſuch perſon who ſhall have right of Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, ſhall not Elect within one Moneth after the vacancy, the Archbiſhop, Biſhop, or Ordinary of the Dioceſs, may under his hand and ſeal Elect a diſcreet perſon of the Pariſh, who after ſuch Subſcription is to ſtand. <hi>This Act is to continue till the end of the firſt Seſſion of the next Parliament.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Canon</hi> 90.5 <hi>Ed.</hi> 6. ch. 1. The Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens are diligently to ſee that all the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhioners duly reſort to their Pariſh Church on Sundays and Holydays, and there con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue the whole time of Divine Service; and none to walk, or ſtand idle, or talking in the Church, Church-yard, or Church-porch during that time; and all ſuch as ſhall be found ſlack or negligent in reſorting to the Church, (having no great or urgent cauſe of abſence) they ſhall earneſtly call upon them; and if they amend not after due Admonition, they muſt preſent their names to the Ordinary of the place.</p>
               <p>1. <hi>El.</hi> ch. 1. <hi>Hobart</hi>'s Rep. fo. 97. If the Churchwardens find any perſon abſent from
<pb n="93" facs="tcp:109137:53"/>the Church upon Sundayes or Holidayes in the time of Divine Service, Preaching or other Holy exerciſe, ſuch perſon is to pay Twelve pence to the uſe of the poor. And this extends as well to all Women Covert, as to other perſons; or the Churchwardens may preſent ſuch offendors in the Eccleſiaſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal Court; but they muſt not pay Twelve pence, and be Preſented too.</p>
               <p>The ſame Forfeiture is againſt all ſuch as open their Shops, or work on Holydayes; which if it were duly put in execution, the poor might be better provided for, but I doubt too many Officers are guilty thereof themſelves.</p>
               <p>4 <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 5. If the Officers find any tipling in any Inn or Alehouſe in the time of Divine Service, then they forfeit 3. <abbr>
                     <hi>s.</hi>
                  </abbr> 4. <abbr>
                     <hi>d.</hi>
                  </abbr> more for Tipling, beſides the Twelve pence for being abſent from the Church: And the Maſter of the houſe that ſuffers them to drink forfeits Ten ſhillings, which forfeitures are to the uſe of the Poor.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Can.</hi> 88. The Churchwardens or Queſt-men &amp; then Aſſiſtants ſhall ſuffer no Plays, Feaſts, Banquets, Suppers, Church Ales, Drinkings, Temporal Courts or Leets, Lay-Juries, Maſters or any other Prophane uſage to be kept in the Church, Chappel or Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard;
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:109137:54"/>neither the Bells to be rung ſuperſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiouſly upon Holydayes or Eves abrogated by the Book of Common Prayer, nor at any other times without good cauſe to be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed by the Miniſter of the place and by themſelves.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Canon</hi> 50.85. Neither the Miniſter, Churchwardens, nor any other Officer of the Church ſhall ſuffer any man to Preach with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in their Churches nor Chappels, but ſuch as by ſhewing their Licenſe to Preach, ſhall appear unto them to be ſufficiently authorized thereunto.</p>
               <p>And the Churchwardens and Queſt-men are alſo to ſee that in every meeting of the Congregation the peace be well kept; and that all perſons Excommunicated and ſo denounced, be kept out of the Church.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Finch,</hi> lib. 2. ch. 17. pag. 179. <hi>Rolls</hi> Caſes, 1. part, fo. 393. Although, as I have ſaid before, the Law doth make Churchwardens a kind of Corporation, and enables them by that name to take moveable Goods and chattels, and to ſue and be ſued at Law concerning ſuch Goods for the uſe and benefit of their Pariſh; yet they cannot take an Eſtate of Lands to them by name of Churchwardens; for if a Feoffment be made to the uſe of the Churchwardens of <hi>H.</hi> this
<pb n="95" facs="tcp:109137:54"/>uſe is void, for they have no capacity to take ſuch purchaſe.</p>
               <p>Neither can Churchwardens preſcribe to have Lands to them and their ſucceſſors, for they are no Corporation to have Lands, but for Goods of the <hi>Church</hi> only.</p>
               <p>If a Bell be broken, the Churchwardens may have an Action againſt him that brake it, and ſhall recover damages, which ſhall be to the uſe of the Pariſh, and not to their own uſe.</p>
               <p>The Churchwardens have no ſuch pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perty in the Goods of the Church, as there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by to have power to give, ſell, releaſe, hurt or impair them, without the aſſent of the Side<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men or Veſtry.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Finch.</hi> lib. 2. ch. 17. pag. 179. If the Churchwardens ſhall give, or impair the goods of the Church in their cuſtody, the Pariſhioners may chooſe new ones, who may have an Account againſt their predeceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors.</p>
               <p>Trin. 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> Ban. Regis. <hi>Rolls</hi> Caſes, 1. part, fol. 393. If the Organs be taken out of the Church, the Churchwardens may bring an Action of Treſpaſs for the ſame; for the Organs belong to the Pariſhioners, and not to the Parſon: and therefore the
<pb n="96" facs="tcp:109137:55"/>Parſon cannot ſue the party in the Eccleſia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtical Court that took them.</p>
               <p>10 <hi>H.</hi> 4 fol. 9.8 <hi>H.</hi> 6. fol. 9. If the Walls, Windows or Doors of the Church be broken down, or the Trees in the Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard be cut down, or the Graſs thereof be eaten up, in this caſe the Parſon or Vicar, and not the Churchwardens, ſhall have an Action for it. A Parſon may bring his Action for breaking and entring into his houſe and cloſe, when it is the Church and Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard.</p>
               <p>Mich. 16 <hi>Jac.</hi> Com. B. Rot. 716. <hi>Smith</hi> and <hi>Pannel</hi>'s Caſe. If the Churchwardens preſent in the Eccleſiaſtical Court, That one <hi>A. B.</hi> one of their Pariſhioners is a Railer, and ſower of Diſcord amongſt his Neighbours, in ſuch caſe there lyes a Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibition; for this belongs to the Leet, and not to the Spiritual Court, unleſs ſuch Railing were in the Church or Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard.</p>
               <p>If the Churchwardens ſue in the Eccle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiaſtical Court for a Church-way which they claim to belong to all the Pariſhioners by preſcription, a Prohibition lyes, for this is a Temporal cauſe.</p>
               <p>If the Churchwardens of <hi>H.</hi> ſue <hi>R. A.</hi> in the Eccleſiaſtical Court, for that he and
<pb n="97" facs="tcp:109137:55"/>all thoſe whoſe Eſtate he hath in ſuch an Houſe, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at the <hi>Perambulation</hi> or <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſion</hi> of the Pariſhioners of the Pariſh, did uſe to provide a Refreſhing for them, with Bread, Cakes, Cheeſe, and Ale, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and ſuffer them to reſt there; in this caſe a Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibition will be grauted, for that they claim it in the nature of a <hi>Corrody.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>A <hi>Corrody</hi> was a reaſonable allowance of meat, drink, bread, money, clothing, lodging, and ſuch like ſuſtenance; which every Founder of <hi>Abbies, Priories, Nun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neries</hi> and other Houſes of <hi>Religion</hi> had in the ſame Houſes when they were ſtanding; for his Father, Brother, Couſin or other man that he would appoint ſhould take it, if it were a houſe of Monks; and if he were a Founder of a houſe of <hi>Nunns</hi> or Women, then the ſame for his Mother, Siſter, Cou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſin or other woman that he would direct thither:</p>
               <p>And alwayes this was provided for, that he that had a <hi>Corrody</hi> in a houſe of Monks, might not ſend a Woman to receive it; nor where a <hi>Corrody</hi> was due in a Nunnery, there it was not lawful to ſend a Man to receive it; for in both caſes ſuch <hi>Preſentation</hi> was to be rejected.</p>
               <p>The Churchwardens are to look to the
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:109137:56"/>repair of the Seats in the Church, but the diſpoſing of the Seats in the Body of the Church belongs of common right to the Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinary of the Dioceſs, ſo that he may place and diſplace whom he pleaſes, except in ſome caſes.</p>
               <p>For, the Ordinary hath nothing to do with the Seats in the Chappels belonging to the houſes of Noble men.</p>
               <p>And if a man and his Anceſtors, and all thoſe whoſe Eſtate he hath in a certain Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuage, have uſed time out of mind to repair an Iſle of the Church, and to ſit there, and none elſe; in ſuch caſe the Ordinary cannot diſplace him, becauſe he hath it by Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcription, for a reaſonable conſideration.</p>
               <p>If a man preſcribe that he and his Ance<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtors, and all thoſe whoſe Eſtate they had in a certain Meſſuage, did uſe to ſit in a certain Seat in the body of the Church time out of mind, in conſideration that he and they have uſed time out of mind to repair the ſaid Seat, if the Ordinary remove him from ſuch Seat, a Prohibition may be brought; for the Ordinary hath no power to diſpoſe of it: for it is a good Preſcription, and by intendment a good conſideration for the ſame.</p>
               <p>But if a man preſcribe to have a Seat in
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:109137:56"/>the body of the Church generally, without conſideration to repair the ſame, in ſuch caſe the Ordinary may diſplace him.</p>
               <p>37 <hi>H.</hi> 6.30. 11 <hi>H.</hi> 7.27. <hi>Canon</hi> 20, 70, 80, 81, 82, 83, 84, 85. The Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens are to ſee that the Church and Churchyard be well repaired and kept clean; and they are to provide Books of Common Prayer, Books of Homilies, a Parchment-Book for Regiſtring of <hi>Chriſtnings, Wed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dings</hi> and <hi>Burials</hi> in; Fonts, Pulpits, Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, Cheſts for Alms, Communion-Cups, Ornaments and other Furniture, and a Cheſt with three Locks and Keys for putting the ſame in: And they are to provide Bread and Wine for the Sacrament, according to the number of the Communicants.</p>
               <p>And they may Rate the Pariſh for money to defray their Charges.</p>
               <p>Their Rates are to be done by the Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens with the aſſent of the greater part of the Pariſhioners, and upon a general warning given before they meet for that purpoſe; And the Eccleſiaſtical Court hath cognizance of the reparation of the Body of the Church.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Co.</hi> 5. Rep. fo. 67. If a man dwell in one Pariſh, and have Lands in another Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh which he occupies there, he may be
<pb n="100" facs="tcp:109137:57"/>charged for ſuch Lands for the Reparation of the Church of the Pariſh where the Lands lye.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Co.</hi> ibid. If an Inhabitant of one Pariſh leaſe out his Lands which he hath in another Pariſh, reſerving Rent, then he ſhall not be charged in the Pariſh where the Lands lye, becauſe there is a pariſhioner and inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitant who may be charged.</p>
               <p>If a man live in one Pariſh and occupy Lands in another Pariſh, he ſhall not be charged in that Pariſh where the Lands lye for the Ornaments of the Church according to his Land; for the Inhabitants only ought to be Rated for them.</p>
               <p>Neither can a man be charged in the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh where he doth inhabit, for the Lands which he occupieth in another Pariſh, to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the Reparation of the Church in the Pariſh where he liveth; becauſe then he might be twice charged, for he may be charged in the Pariſh where the Land lyes.</p>
               <p>M. 13 <hi>Jac. C. B.</hi> If there be a Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel of Eaſe within a Pariſh, and one part of the Pariſh have uſed time out of mind to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pair the Chappel themſelves without the reſt of the pariſhioners, and there to hear Service and Marry, and all other things, but
<pb n="101" facs="tcp:109137:57"/>only that they Bury at the Mother-Church; notwithſtanding they muſt contribute to the reparation of the Mother-Church.</p>
               <p>If ſome pariſhioners be Rated and others are not, and thoſe who are rated are ſued in the Eccleſiaſtical Court, they muſt plead this matter in this Court, for they cannot have a <hi>Prohibition.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Where there are five Bells in a Church, and the major part of the pariſhioners agree that there ſhall be made a ſixth Bell, which is made accordingly, and they make a Rate for the payment of it, this ſhall bind the remainder of the pariſhioners though they did not agree unto it; otherwiſe any obſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate perſons might hinder any thing in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended, and what is fit for the Ornament of the Church. <hi>Heckfield</hi> and <hi>Mattingly,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Every man ought to be rated according to his perſonal Eſtate, and not according to his Lands for the Goods and Ornaments of the Church; and by a Land-rate for Church-reparations, though the occupier of the Lands live in another Pariſh.</p>
               <p>Theſe things are accounted Church-reparations, and are to be performed by a Land-rate, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Walls of the Church and Steeple, the Churchyard Walls or Rails; the
<pb n="102" facs="tcp:109137:58"/>Windows and Barrs of Iron, and Glaſs, the Roof of Timber, with Laths, Nails, Prigs, Dogs and Bolts of Iron, the covering of Lead, Tyle, Slates or Shingles, the Floor with Stone or Paving-Tyle, the Doors with Locks, Keys, ridges, Hooks and Nails; the furniture of the Steeple, with Stairs, Floors, Bells, Wheels and Ropes; the Pul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pit, and the Pews and Seats not made by private men.</p>
               <p>Theſe following are to be rated on the Inhabitants of the Pariſh, and not upon out-dwellers, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Communion-table and coverings thereof, the Communion-cups, the Bread and Wine for the Communicants, the Bible and other Books appointed to be in Churches, the Waſhing of the Communion-clothes, Candles for Lecture-dayes, the Surplice, Pulpit-cloth and Cuſhion, the Clerk and Sextons wages, and expences of the Churchwardens and Sides-men about the Pariſh-buſineſs.</p>
               <p>The Churchwardens are to joyn with the Conſtables in making of Rates for the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lief of the poor maimed Souldiers and Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riners, and for conveying Priſoners to the Gaol, and to execute Warrants for the ſame.</p>
               <pb n="103" facs="tcp:109137:58"/>
               <p> 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 2. The Churchwardens are to joyn with the Conſtables in the chooſing of <hi>Surveyors for the Highways,</hi> and in the ſetting down of dayes for the work, and in the overſight of the <hi>High-Constables</hi> Account for the money they do receive up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on any Forfeitures about the <hi>Highwayes;</hi> And they may with the ayd of two Juſtices (one of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) force <hi>High-Conſtables</hi> to account for and pay in what money they have received forfeited for default of High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes; And to execute the Juſtices <hi>war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants</hi> for the penalties and forfeitures about cleanſing the Street and repairing the High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes.</p>
               <p>18 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 4. The Churchwardens and Overſeers of the poor are to execute the Juſtices <hi>Warrant</hi> for levying the penalty of Five pounds upon the parties Goods that is not Buried in <hi>Woollen,</hi> which penalty is to be employed to the uſe of the Poor.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Cor.</hi> 2. ch. 2. the Churchwardens in <hi>London, Weſtminſter,</hi> and Borough of <hi>South-wark,</hi> &amp;c. upon every Tueſday or Wedneſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day in <hi>Eaſter-week,</hi> together with the Conſtable, Overſeers of the poor, and Surveyors of Highwayes in every Pariſh re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectively, or the greater number of them; giving notice, or calling together ſuch other
<pb n="104" facs="tcp:109137:59"/>inhabitants of their Pariſhes as have formerly born the like Offices, they or the greater number of them are to make choice of, and ſhall nominate and appoint two or more able perſons that are Tradeſmen of their pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh to be <hi>Scvengers</hi> for the Streets, Lanes, and other open paſſages of each Ward or diviſion within the ſaid Pariſh for the Year next following, and until others be choſen and ſetled in their places.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Canon</hi> 89. The Churchwardens at the end of their Year, or within one Month af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter at the moſt, are before the Miniſter and Pariſhioners to give up a juſt Account of their Receipts and Disburſements; and at their going out of their Office they are to deliver up to the Pariſhioners what Money or other things of right belonging unto the Church which they have remaining in their hands, that it may be delivered over by them unto the next Churchwardens by Bill indented.</p>
               <p>If the Churchwardens refuſe to do this, they may be <hi>preſented</hi> at the next Viſitation-Court for it, or the ſucceeding Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens may bring their Action of Account againſt them at the Common Law, and compell them to it; and in this account they ſhall be allowed their needful Disburſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:109137:59"/>and Expences about the Pariſh buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Canon</hi> 116. The Churchwardens, Queſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men or Sides-men ſhall not be bound to exhi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bit their <hi>Preſentments</hi> about once a Year where it hath been no oftner uſed, nor above twice a year in any Dioceſs what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, except it be at the Biſhops Viſita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; for the which <hi>Preſentments</hi> of every pariſh Church or Chappel, the Regiſter of the Court where they are to be exhibited ſhall not receive above Four pence in one Year, under pain of Suſpenſion from the execution of his Office, the ſpace of one Month for every offence <hi>toties quoties;</hi> But the Churchwardens may voluntarily preſent oftner if they pleaſe.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Canon</hi> 117. No Churchwardens, Queſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men or Sides-men ſhall be called or cited but only at the time or times before limited, to appear before any Eccleſiaſtical Judge whatſoever, for refuſing at other times to preſent any faults committed in their Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes, and puniſhable by Eccleſiaſtical Laws; neither ſhall they or any of them, after their Preſentments exhibited, at any of thoſe times be any farther troubled for the ſame. Except it evidently appear that they did willingly and wittingly omit to preſent ſome
<pb n="106" facs="tcp:109137:60"/>publick crime or crimes as they knew to have been committed, or could not be igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant that there was then a publick fame of them; or unleſs there be very juſt cauſe to call them to explain their former Preſentments: And in caſe of wilful omiſſion, their Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinaries ſhall proceed againſt them in ſuch ſort, as in cauſes of wilful Perjury in a Court Eccleſiaſtical, it is already by Law pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Canon</hi> 113, 118. One of the two times of <hi>Preſentments</hi> is alwayes to be about a week or fortnight after <hi>Eaſter,</hi> at which time alſo the old Churchwardens are to leave their office, and new ones are to come in; but the new ones are not to be Sworn till the old ones have given in their Preſentments; and every Parſon or Vicar, or their Curates in their abſence, are to joyn in the preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment with the Churchwardens, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and if the Churchwardens refuſe to preſent, then every ſuch Parſon and Vicar, or in their ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence their Curates may themſelves preſent to their Ordinaries at all ſuch times, and when elſe they ſhall think fit.</p>
               <div type="articles">
                  <pb n="107" facs="tcp:109137:60"/>
                  <head>The ſumm of the <hi>Articles</hi> uſually given to the Churchwardens to make their <hi>Preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments</hi> upon are theſe, <hi>viz.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p n="1">1. Whether their Church and Chancel, Bells and Ropes be in good repair, and the Ten Commandments, Lords Prayer and Creed drawn out in fair Letters, the Kings Arms ſet up, Aſſeſſments made for the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pair of the Church, and who refuſes to pay?</p>
                  <p>If they have a Font, Communion-Table, Carpet, Table-cloth, Flagons with Cups and Cover for Bread and Wine, a Reading-Desk, a Pulpit with a Cuſhion and Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring for it, a fit Common-Prayer-Book of the largeſt volume, the Bible in <hi>folio</hi> of the laſt Tranſlation, with a Book of Homilies, and Book of Canons, and a Surplice?</p>
                  <p>If the Tombs, Monuments and Grave-ſtones be ſafely kept from removing and breaking?</p>
                  <p>A Book of Parchment for Regiſtring Chriſtnings, weddings, and Burials, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> a Cheſt with three locks to put the ſame and the Church-Ornaments in, with a Box for Alms, and a Table of degrees Prohibiting Marriage hung up in the Church?</p>
                  <p>If the Parſonage-houſe and Out-houſes be
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:109137:61"/>in good Repair, and the Churchyard well fenced to keep out Swine? <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="2">2. Whether the Parſon, Vicas, or Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate read the Common Prayer at Morning and Evening Service, wear his Surplice, bid dayes, Preach every Sunday, or read an Homily, Catechiſe, obſerve the Fifth of <hi>November,</hi> Thirtyeth of <hi>January,</hi> Twenty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty-ninth of <hi>May,</hi> and Second of <hi>September;</hi> and obſerve Perambulations, or going the Bounds in <hi>Rogation-week,</hi> preach ſound Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctrine, and vent no Sedition againſt the King or Government; celebrate the Lords Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per three times every Year at leaſt, whereof at <hi>Eaſter</hi> for one; Baptize Infants with Godfathers and Godmothers, viſit the Sick and pray with them, Bury the dead accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the Book of Common Prayer, Marry none clandeſtinely, Preach in his Gown, be a man of a ſober and chaſt life, a Peace<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maker amongſt his Neighbours, and one that takes care to reduce Sectaries. Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſants, Separatiſts and Refractory Parſons to the obedience and doctrine of the Church, and reads the book of Canons to the people at leaſt once every Year, and the 39. Arti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles Twice every year?</p>
                  <p n="3">
                     <pb n="109" facs="tcp:109137:61"/> 3. Whether all their Pariſhioners of due age reſort to the Church to Divine Service, behave themſelves reverently there, kneel, ſtand up, and make Anſwer to the Rubrick of the Common Prayer book? whether any work, or ſell wares on Sundayes or Holydays, or whether Vintners, Victualers, Inn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keepers or others to receive any to drink in their houſes in the time of Divine Service?</p>
                  <p>Whether any Marry within the Degrees forbidden, or be Adulterers, Swearers, Blaſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phemers, Drunkards?</p>
                  <p>If any above Sixteen years of age do not receive the Lords Supper three times a year, whereof <hi>Eaſter</hi> to be one?</p>
                  <p>If any keep their Children Unchriſtned, Women that come not to be Churched, or any bring not their dead to be Buried after the Service of the Church? Or if any be Married without Banes or Licenſe at unlaw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful hours?</p>
                  <p n="4">4. Whether their Pariſh-Clerk and Sex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton (if they have any) be duly choſen, can write and read, be of an honeſt life, and make the Reſponſes to the Hymns and other Suffrages?</p>
                  <p>And if the School-Maſter, Phyſitian, Chi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rurgeon, and Midwife (if they have any)
<pb n="110" facs="tcp:109137:62"/>Teach or Preach without Licenſe? If the Churchwardens be duly choſen according to the <hi>Canon</hi> and Cuſtom? <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="11" type="chapter">
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. XI.</hi> The Office of the Overſeers of the Poor.</head>
               <p>ST at. 43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 2. 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> chap. 28. The <hi>Overſeers of the Poor</hi> are to be choſen yearly and joyned with the Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens of the <hi>Pariſh,</hi> in the overſight and ordering of the Poor of the Pariſh; They are to be choſen by two or more Juſtices of the peace, (one whereof to be of the <hi>Quo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum</hi>) who are yearly under their hands and ſeals, at <hi>Eaſter</hi> or within one Month after, to appoint four, three, or two ſubſtantial Houſholders, according to the greatneſs of the <hi>Pariſh,</hi> to be joyned with the Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens to look to the <hi>Poor</hi> of the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh.</p>
               <p>Stat. 43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 2. The major part of these Officers without the reſt may do any thing belonging to their office, but they are to have the allowance and conſent of two
<pb n="111" facs="tcp:109137:62"/>Juſtices of peace (one of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) to every thing they do about their office. And theſe Officers, or ſuch of them as are not hindred by juſt excuſe, (to be allowed by two Juſtices) are to meet monthly in the Church on Sunday after Evening Prayer, to conſider of matters concerning their office, and to uſe all poſſible diligence in their office, on pain of Twenty ſhillings for every ſuch de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 40. ſo. 98. The Parents that are able to work, and may have work, are to find their Children by their labour, and not the Pariſh; but if they be over-charged with Children, the <hi>Overſeers</hi> are to help them, by putting out ſome of their Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren Apprentices.</p>
               <p>Stat. 43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> chap. 3. <hi>Reſolu. Judges,</hi> 16, 17. The Father, Grandfather, and the Children and Grandchildren of every poor impotent perſon not able to work, (be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of ſufficient ability) ſhall relieve ſuch poor perſons in ſuch manner as the Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of the peace of that County where ſuch ſufficient perſon dwelleth, at their general Quarter-Seſſions ſhall Aſſeſs. And if ſuch party refuſe to abide the Order, they forfeit Twenty ſhillings for every Month to the <hi>Poor</hi> of the Pariſh; which
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:109137:63"/>forfeiture is to be levied by the Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens and Overſeers, or one of them, by Warrant from two Juſtices (one of the <hi>Quo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum</hi>) by diſtreſs and ſale of the offendors goods; and for want of Diſtreſs two ſuch Juſtices may commit the offendor to pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, there to remain till the ſaid Forfeiture be paid.</p>
               <p>But if a man marry a Grandmother that hath no Eſtate, the Grandfather-in-Law is not chargeable; but if ſhe have an Eſtate cauſed without ſuch Marriage, or that comes after Marriage by deſcent or otherwiſe to her, here he may be charged; but he can be charged in no caſe longer than his Wife lives.</p>
               <p>Baſtard-children are not within this Law, neither can the Juſtices do any thing here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in againſt a man that lives out of their County.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Reſol. Judges,</hi> 15. No Poor may beg but in their own Pariſh, and there by Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſe of the Overſeers of the poor; and they may not licenſe them to beg in the High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes there.</p>
               <p>1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 7. No inhabitants may ſerve any Poor at their door but thoſe of their own Pariſh, that have Licenſe from the
<pb n="113" facs="tcp:109137:63"/>Overſeers of the poor to Beg, on pain of Ten ſhillings for every default.</p>
               <p>Stat. 43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 2. The Overſeers to make proviſion for a poor man that wants a houſe, (but not for a common Herdſman or Shep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herd) with conſent of the Lord of the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor by writing under his hand and ſeal, ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther by themſelves or with a Seſſions order, may erect a Cottage upon any part of the Waſte of the Manor, and lodge inmates therein, notwithſtanding the Statute of 31 <hi>El.</hi> 7. but ſuch Cottage muſt not be any otherwiſe employed.</p>
               <p>Stat. 4.3 <hi>El.</hi> ch. 2. All ſuch perſons mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried or unmarried, having no means to main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain them, uſe no ordinary and dayly Trade to get their living by, and ſuch perſons as can get no work, are to be ſet on work by the Overſeers; and any one Juſtice of peace may ſend to the Houſe of Correction or com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Gaol ſuch as ſhall not employ them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves to work, being appointed thereto by the Churchwardens and Overſeers of the poor.</p>
               <p>Stat. 3 <hi>Car.</hi> 1. ch. 4. The Churchwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and Overſeers of the poor, with the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent of two or more Juſtices of the peace (one of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) may ſet up and uſe any Trade, <hi>Myſtery</hi> or Occupation, for the
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:109137:64"/>ſetting on Work and better relief of the Poor of the Pariſh, Town or place where they are Overſeers.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. chap. 12. If a ſtranger come into a Pariſh, into any houſe under the yearly Rent of Ten pounds <hi>per annum,</hi> the Overſeers may require ſufficient ſecurity of him for the diſcharge of the Pariſh; and if he refuſe, they may complain to the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices of the peace within forty dayes after the parties coming to the Pariſh, and they may order him to give ſecurity, or otherwiſe remove him.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. chap. 40. fol. 94, 95. The Overſeers are to take and put out Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tices, ſuch poor mens children as are brought up idly and looſely, or ſuch as are a bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den and charge to their Pariſh: and they muſt have regad to put them to ſuch Maſters as are of ability and honeſty, that ſhall not provoke their Apprentices to run away by hard uſage; nor ſuffer them to conſume their time without learning their Trade. And they are to put out their Children Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tices while they are young and tractable, (ſo they be above ſeven years of age) for elſe by reaſon of their idle and baſe bringing up, they will hardly keep their ſervice, or employ themſelves to work.</p>
               <pb n="115" facs="tcp:109137:64"/>
               <p> 7 <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 3. Theſe Apprentices are to be choſen out of the pooreſt ſort of Children whoſe parents are leaſt able to maintain them, and they muſt be above Seven, and under Fifteen years of age when they are firſt bound.</p>
               <p>43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> chap. 2. <hi>Dalt.</hi> ch. 31. fol. 83. The Overſeers are to have the conſent of two Juſtices of the peace in the putting out of ſuch Apprentices, and they may bind the Man-child till 24. years of age, and the Woman-child till 21. or till ſhe be married, which ſhall firſt happen: And theſe Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices may be bound to Weavers, Maſons, Dyers, Fullers, or any other Trade as well as to Husbandry or Houſwifery.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Reſol. Judges,</hi> 1633. <hi>Queſt.</hi> 1. The Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices may be put to any man whom the Overſeers and Juſtices ſhall think fit within the ſame Pariſh, or elſewhere in other Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes within the ſame Hundred, either with or without money; But if the Child be young, and the party to whom they place it not very able, then they may give mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney if they pleaſe, as the party and they can agree.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Reſol. Judges, Q.</hi> 4. All men that have or may have uſe for Servants, as Knights, Clergymen, Gentlemen, and Yeomen, as
<pb n="116" facs="tcp:109137:65"/>well as Tradeſmen are bound to take Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices; yea, though wealthy men Table themſelves, or live ſo privately that they have no uſe for a Servant, yet they may be compelled to take them; or elſe to pay a ſumm of money for putting them Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices elſewhere; and if they refuſe to pay the ſumm impoſed upon them, two Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices of the peace may make their Warrant to leavy the ſame by diſtreſs and ſale of the offendors goods.</p>
               <p>Or the refuers to take Apprentices may be preſented and indicted for the ſame, upon the Statute of 43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 2.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Reſol. Judges, Queſt.</hi> 2. An Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice put to a man in reſpect of his Farm, when his Leaſe expireth the Apprentice ſhall go ſtill with the Farm, if the firſt Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter be ſo pleaſed; otherwiſe it is where an Apprentice is put to a man in reſpect of his abilities, or for other reſpects. And where any diffeences are between the Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers and the man that is to receive an Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentice, about money, and what money ſhall be given, or otherwiſe; the Juſtices thereabouts, or in their defaults the Seſſions muſt determine it.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 40, &amp; 31. fo. 96, &amp; 78. If the parents of poor Children ſhall refuſe
<pb n="117" facs="tcp:109137:65"/>to let their Children be put out Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tices (without good cauſe ſhewed) ſuch Parents may be bound over by the Juſtices, to anſwer their ſaid default; And if the Children ſhall refuſe, the Juſtices may ſend them to the Houſe of Correction, there to remain till they be content to be Bound and ſerve.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 31. fo. 82. Theſe Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices muſt be bound by Indenture, and not by any verbal Agreement; and the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture muſt be either between the Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, Churchwardens, and Overſeers or ſome of them, and the Apprentice on the one part, and him that takes the Apprentice on the other part. And he muſt be named by the name of an <hi>Apprentice</hi> expreſly, or elſe he is no Apprentice, though he be bound.</p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="form_of_indenture">
                  <body>
                     <head>The form of an <hi>Indenture</hi> for a poor Child put out by the Pariſh.</head>
                     <p>
                        <hi>THis</hi> Indenture <hi>made the</hi> 25th. <hi>day of</hi> M. <hi>&amp;c. Witneſſeth, That</hi> R. H. <hi>and</hi> R. W. <hi>Overſeers for the Poor in the Pariſh of</hi> H. <hi>in the County of</hi> S. <hi>and</hi> H.T. <hi>Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warden of the ſame pariſh; by and with the conſent of</hi> A. H. <hi>Knight and Baronet, and</hi>
                        <pb n="118" facs="tcp:109137:66"/>F. T. <hi>Eſq; two of His Majeſties Justices of the peace of the ſame County, have by theſe preſents placed and bound</hi> J. G. <hi>(being a poor fatherleſs child) as an Apprentice with</hi> E. B. <hi>of</hi> H. <hi>aforeſaid widow, and as an Apprentice with her the ſaid</hi> E. B. <hi>to dwell from the day of the date of theſe preſents, until ſhe the ſaid</hi> J. G. <hi>ſhall come to the age of</hi> 21. <hi>years, or be married, which ſhall firſt happen, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Statute in that caſe made and provided; by and during all ſuch time and term the ſaid</hi> J. G. <hi>ſhall the ſaid</hi> E. B. <hi>her Dame well and faithfully ſerve in all ſuch lawful buſineſs as the ſaid</hi> E. B. <hi>ſhall put her the ſaid</hi> J. G. <hi>unto, according to her power, wit and ability, and honeſtly and obe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diently in all things ſhall be have her ſelf to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards her ſaid Dame and children and all the reſt of the Family of the ſaid</hi> E. B. <hi>And the ſaid</hi> E. B. <hi>for her part, promiſeth, co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venanteth and agreeth, That ſhe the ſaid</hi> E. B. <hi>the ſaid</hi> J. G. <hi>in the Art and skill of Huſwifry, the beſt manner that ſhe can or may ſhall teach and inform, or cauſe to be taught and informed as much as thereunto belongeth, and ſhe the ſaid</hi> E. B. <hi>knoweth; And alſo during all the ſaid term to find and allow unto her ſaid Apprentice meat, drink, linen, woollen, hoſe, ſhooes, waſhing, lodge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,
<pb n="119" facs="tcp:109137:66"/>and all other things fitting or meet for an Apprentice.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>In witneſs whereof, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                        </signed>
                     </closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <p>Stat. 1. <hi>Jac.</hi> ch. 25. 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> chap. 28. This Binding is as effectual to all purpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſes as if the Children were of full age, and did bind themſelves by Indentures and Covenants; and all ſuch as are bound by the Overſeers as aboveſaid may ſafely be received and kept as Apprentices by their Maſters.</p>
               <p>Stat. 7 <hi>Jac.</hi> chap. 3. Such money as is given to put out poor Children Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tices, is to be employed in Corporate-Towns by the Corporations and in other places by the Parſon &amp; Vicar, with the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables, Churchwardens or Overſeers of the Poor, or the moſt part of them; who ſhall employ the ſame accordingly on pain or for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit 5. Marks each of th em ſo making default, to be divided betwixt the Poor of the pariſh and the Proſecutor.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> The party taking any money with ſuch Apprentice ſhall give good ſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity by Obligation to repay it again at the end of ſeven years next enſuing the date of the ſaid Obligation, or within three Months next after the end of the ſaid ſeven Years;
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:109137:67"/>and if ſuch Apprentice ſhall dye within 7. years, then within one Year after his or her death; and if the Maſter, Miſtreſs, or Dame happen to dye within 7. Years, then within one Year after their death; ſo as the money may be employed in placing the Apprentice with ſome other of the ſame Trade to ſerve out his time.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> Money ſo given ſhall be employed within three Months after the Receipt thereof; And if there ſhall not be apt perſons found in the places where it is given, to be Apprentices, it ſhall then be employed in the Pariſhes next adjoyning by the parties that are truſted with it in the place where it was ſo given, and there alſo Bond ſhall be taken.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Reſol. Judges.</hi> If a Woman unmarried be hired weekly, monethly, half-yearly or yearly in one Pariſh, and there be begotten with Child, and then goeth into another Pariſh, and there is ſetled in ſervice or otherwiſe for two or three Months, and then ſhe is diſcovered to be with Child; in this caſe ſhe and her Child ſhall be ſetled in the Pariſh where ſhe then is, and muſt not be ſent to the Pariſh from whence ſhe came.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Reſol. Judges.</hi> If a Woman be delivered of a Baſtard child in one Pariſh, and then go
<pb n="121" facs="tcp:109137:67"/>into another Pariſh with her Child, in this caſe the Child after it is nurſed is to be ſent to and ſetled in the place where it was born, and not to remain with the Mother.</p>
               <p>Stat. 43 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 2. Theſe Officers or the greater part of them (for performing their of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice) may raiſe weekly or otherwiſe by Taxa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of every Parſon, Vicar, and other occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pier of Land, Houſe, or Tythes; Coal-mines or ſaleable Underwoods within the Pariſh, Town, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſuch a ſumm as they ſhall think fit. And this Rate they muſt have allowed and confirmed undr the hands of two Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces (one of the <hi>Quorum;</hi>) and by warrant from them or any two Juſtices they may levy the ſaid Tax by diſtreſs and ſale of the goods of the party refuſing to pay, rendring the overplus to the owners; and in default of diſtreſs, two ſuch Juſtices may commit the party to priſon, there to remain without Bayl till he pay it.</p>
               <p>Theſe Rates ought to be well and truly made according to mens viſible Eſtates, real and perſonal, within the place only, and not for any Eſtate elſewhere.</p>
               <p>Theſe Rates muſt be ſet upon the Tenants and occupiers of Lands, and not upon the Landlords, living within or without the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh; for the Tenant only is chargeable for the Land.</p>
               <pb n="122" facs="tcp:109137:68"/>
               <p> 
                  <hi>Reſol. Judges.</hi> The Parſon having a full Tenth part of the profits of the place, may be rated to a Tenth part.</p>
               <p>The Rate or ſtock for Goods is thought reaſonable to be ſet after the proportion of Lands, <hi>(viz.)</hi> an 100 Pound in ſtock to be rated after 5 or 6 Pounds a year in Lands.</p>
               <p>If any perſons find themſelves aggrieved in any Tax or other act done by the Overſeers, or by the Juſtices of peace, they are to ſeek for relief at the Quarter-Seſſions.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="12" type="chapter">
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. XII.</hi> The office of the Surveyors of High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes and Bridges.</head>
               <p>14 <hi>CAR.</hi> 2. ch. 6. The Churchwardens, Conſtables or Tythingmen of every Pariſh, Town or Hamlett for the time being, are upon Monday or Tueſday in <hi>Eaſter-week,</hi> with the advice of the major part of the Inhabitants, to chuſe two or more inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants of the Pariſh, Town or Hamlett to be <hi>Surveyors of the High-wayes</hi> for the Year following, and they are to give notice there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of in writing to the perſons choſen next Sun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day after; and for default of ſuch Choyce, the Conſtables, Churchwardens, and inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitants
<pb n="123" facs="tcp:109137:68"/>of every Pariſh, Town or Hamlett ſhall forfeit and loſe Five pounds.</p>
               <p>After choyce made of theſe <hi>Surveyors</hi> and notice given them, they are forthwith to take the Office upon them, on pain to forfeit Twenty ſhillings.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 6. Highways muſt be ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciently amended at the charge of the whole Town; and it is not enough for the Inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitants to do their full ſix dayes work yearly, except their Wayes be all well and ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciently repaired thereby; for if all their ſaid Wayes be not ſufficiently amened, the whole Town may be indicted for it; and if ſix dayes work in the year will not ſerve to amend them, the Surveyors muſt appoint more dayes.</p>
               <p>The owner of Lands, if he be not the occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pier thereof, ought not to be charged towards the repair of the common Highwayes; but the Tenant who occupies the Land is to be charged therewith.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J.P. ch. 26. fol. 68. The Surveyors are to ſee that the pariſhioners do their work on the dayes appointed, and that they ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve theſe Rules, <hi>(viz.)</hi> every perſon having in his own occupation a Plough-Land in Tillage or in Paſture in the ſame Pariſh, or keeping there a Plough or Draught, ſhall
<pb n="124" facs="tcp:109137:69"/>find and ſend on every day to the place appointed by the Surveyors, one Wayn or Cart after the faſhion of the Countrey pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided with Horſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> fit for the Carriage, and with neceſſary Tools fit for the work; and with two able men, who are there to do ſuch work with their Wayns, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as they ſhall be appointed (by the Surveyors) by the ſpace of eight Hours every of the ſaid ſix dayes, on pain of Ten ſhillings every day default is made.</p>
               <p>Stat. 2 <hi>&amp;</hi> 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> ch. 8. Every other Houſholder, Cottager and Labourer of the Pariſh, Town, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> (able to labour, and being no hired ſervant by the year) muſt by himſelf or ſome other able man, be then and there ready to work every of the ſaid ſix dayes, by the ſpace of eight hours as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid; where they ſhall be appointed by the Surveyors, on pain to forfeit Twelve pence for every day they make default.</p>
               <p>18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 9. All perſons being charge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able but as Cottagers by the 2 &amp; 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> yet if they be in Subſidy 5 Pounds in Goods, or 40 Shillings in Lands, or above, they muſt find two able men to work every of the ſaid ſix dayes.</p>
               <p>2 <hi>&amp;</hi> 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> ch. 8. If any of the Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riages ſhall not be thought needful by the
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:109137:69"/>ſaid Surveyors upon any of the ſaid dayes, they may appoi nt in ſtead of a Team two able men to work as aforeſaid, who ſhall not fail in pain that the party who ſhould ſend them ſhall forfeit Twelve pence for every day that either of them makes default.</p>
               <p>18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 9. He that ſhall occupy a Plough-Land in tillage or in paſture, lying in ſeveral Pariſhes, ſhall be chargeable only in the Pariſh where he dwelleth, and he that occupieth ſeveral Plough Lands in ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Pariſhes ſhall be charged in each Town or Pariſh where ſuch Land lyeth, <hi>(viz.)</hi> to find in each Town or Pariſh, one Cart furniſhed as aforeſaid, though he be no in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitant there.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Co.</hi> on <hi>Lit.</hi> fo. 69. It is ſaid that a Plough-Land is not alwayes of one content, but or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinarily it is ſo much as one Plough may plough in on eyear; which is on ſome Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries more, and in ſome leſs, according to the heavineſs of the ſoil.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Co.</hi> 4. Rep. fo. 37. b. <hi>&amp;</hi> 9 Rep. fo. 124. A Plough-Land or Carve-Land may contain Houſe, Meadow, Paſture and Wood; and if one have ſo much of this as will keep a Plough, and yield Tillage for it, if part of it were eared, in this caſe it ſeems he is to ſend his Plough.</p>
               <pb n="126" facs="tcp:109137:70"/>
               <p> 
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. chap. 26. fo. 72. He that keepeth a Plough or Draught for carriage, although he occupy little or no Land, but carrieth or plougheth for other men, yet it ſeems he is to ſend his Cart to the High-wayes; and if a may keep only two Horſes and a Cart for his own buſineſs, he is to come with his Cart and two Horſes, with a Man to drive them.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 6. If ſix dayes will not ſerve for repairing of the Highwayes, the Surveyors may appoint more, and charge all perſons within their limits who are chargeable by the Law to come to the work; but the Surveyors are to pay them for their work for all the dayes above ſix dayes, according to the Rates of the Countrey; and if they can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not agree, the next Juſtice of the peace living out of the Pariſh is to determine the buſineſs between them.</p>
               <p>5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 13. The Surveyors, if they ſee cauſe, for the amendment of the High-wayes, may take and carry away ſo much of the rubbiſh and ſmalleſt broken ſtones of any mans Quarray lying within the ſame Pariſh without leave of the owner, as they ſhall think needful; or gather the loo ſe ſtones lying diſperſed in any mans grounds: But they may not without licenſe dig in any mans
<pb n="127" facs="tcp:109137:70"/>Quarrey for new ſtones, nor take the great ſtones already digged; and if there be no ſuch rubbiſh to be found in any mans Quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rey within the ſaid Pariſh, then they may enter into any mans ſeveral ground within the ſaid Pariſh, lying near the place where the Wayes are decayed, and there (if they ſee any hopes of finding materals fit for the reparation thereof) without leave of the owner they may dig for Sand, Stones, Gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vel, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſo that it be not in the Houſes, Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chards, Gardens or Meadows of any man; they are not to come there without licenſe of the owner. And in ſuch place where they may dig without leave, they are not to make a pit above ten yards in breadth or length; and they are to take care that the place be filled up again at the charge of the Pariſh within one Month after, upon pain to forfeit five Marks to the owner of the ground, to be recovered by Action of Debt.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 6. The ſame power is granted to Surveyors to dig for Gravel, Chalk, Sand, Stones, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in any mans ground in the pariſh next adjoyning to the place where the Wayes are in decay, if there be not ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient in the ſame pariſh: Provided it be not in the Houſe, Garden, Orchard, Court, Yard, Park with Deer in it, or in the Meadow
<pb n="128" facs="tcp:109137:71"/>of ſuch party, without paying any thing for the ſame Gravel, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> only damages to the party for the carrying the ſame over his graſs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> filling up the pits as is before men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, (5 <hi>Eliz.</hi>) within the ſame time, and under the ſame penalty.</p>
               <p>Stat. 5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> chap. 13.8 <hi>Eliz.</hi> chap. 10. If the owners of the grounds next adjoyning to the Highwayes do not keep their Hedges low, and cut down their Trees and Buſhes growing on the ſame Wayes, they forfeit Ten ſhillings.</p>
               <p>And he that ſcowrs not his Ditches in the ground next adjoyning to the ground that is next the Highway, that the water may paſs the better out of the Highway, ſhall forfeit 12 <abbr>
                     <hi>d.</hi>
                  </abbr> for every Rod ſo left unſcowred.</p>
               <p>Stat. 18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> chap. 10. If any ſcowr his Ditch by the HIghways ſide, and throw the ſoyl thereof into the highway, and ſuffer it to lye there ſix Months, he forfeits for every Load thereof 12 <abbr>
                     <hi>d.</hi>
                  </abbr> And the Surveyors are to make Sluces where ſuch Banks have been heretofore made, for carrying away the water out of the Highway.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J.P. ch. 26. fo. 70. Every Survey or may cauſe any Water-courſe or Spring of water being in the Highway (within their pariſh) to be turned into another mans ſeveral
<pb n="129" facs="tcp:109137:71"/>ditch or ground next adjoyning to the ſaid Way, in ſuch manner as by the diſcretion of the Surveyors ſhall be thought meet.</p>
               <p>Stat. 18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 10. <hi>Wingate</hi> Abr. Stat. Tit. <hi>Highwayes.</hi> The forfeitures of the Act of 18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 10. muſt be levied by the Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors for the time being (by warrant from the Juſtices before whom the party ſhall be convict) by diſtreſs and ſale of goods; which forfeitures are to be employed towards the amendment of the Highwayes: and if the Surveyors neglect to do it within one year after the offence committed, then the Conſtables and Churchwardens by like Warrant may do it.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Dalt.</hi> J.P. ch. 26. fo. 70. Stat. 5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 13. The Surveyors or one of them are to preent to the next Juſtice of peace every default upon the 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> and 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> of <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> ch. 8. and 5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 13. within one Month after it ſhall be made, on pain of 40 <abbr>
                     <hi>s.</hi>
                  </abbr> and the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice is in pain of 5 <abbr>
                     <hi>l.</hi>
                  </abbr> to certifie the ſame at the next Quarter Seſſions; where the Juſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces are to enquire of the default, and ſet ſuch Fine upon the offendors as they or two of them (one of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) ſhall think fit.</p>
               <p>5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 13. <hi>Raſtall</hi> 199. The preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of a Juſtice of peace in Seſſions upon his own knowledge ſhall be a good con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viction;
<pb n="130" facs="tcp:109137:72"/>upon which the Juſtices in Seſſions or two of them (one of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) may aſſeſs a Fine as well upon a Verdict, but the offendor ſhall be admitted to his Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe.</p>
               <p>Stat. 2 <hi>&amp;</hi> 3. <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> ch. 8.5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 13.18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 10. The offences upon theſe Statutes are inquirable by Juſtices of the peace-in their Seſſions, and Stewards in Leets; either of which have power to aſſeſs Fines at their diſcretions upon defaulters, (of which Fines, indented Eſtreats in the Seſſions under the hand and ſeal of the Clerk of the Peace, in the Leet under the hand and ſeal of the Steward) ſhall be delivered within ſix Weeks after <hi>Michaelmas;</hi> one part of the Eſtreats to the Bayliff or High-Conſtable of the Liberty, and the other part to the Conſtables and Churchwardens of the Pariſh where the offendors live.</p>
               <p>Stat. 2 <hi>&amp;</hi> 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> chap. 8. Theſe Eſtreats ſhall be a ſufficient Warrant for the Bayliff or chief Conſtable of the Liberty to levy the ſaid Fines by way of diſtreſs; and if no diſtreſs can be found, or the party do not pay the fine within Twenty dayes after the lawful demand thereof, he or they ſhall forfeit double ſo much; All which Fines and Forſeitures are to be employed towards
<pb n="131" facs="tcp:109137:72"/>the mending of the Highwayes in the Pariſh where the offences are committed.</p>
               <p>Stat. 2 <hi>&amp;</hi> 3 <hi>P.</hi> &amp; <hi>M.</hi> ch. 8. The High-Conſtable or Bayliff ſhall between the Firſt of <hi>March</hi> and Laſt of <hi>April</hi> yearly give an account to the Conſtables and Churchwar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens, who have the other part of the Eſtreats of the Fines, of what Money they have re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived on pain of Forty ſhillings; and the Conſtables and Churchwardens have power to call the High-Conſtable or Bayliff before two or more Juſtices of the peace (one whereof to be of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) to give up his Account; who have power to commit him until he have ſatisfied all the Arrerages by him received, ſave Eight pence in the Pound for his own Fee, and Twelve pence in the Pound for the Clerk of the Peace, or Steward of the Leet. And the Contables and Churchwardens have the ſame power ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſively as their predeceſſors.</p>
               <p>14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 6. Every Survey or of the Highwayes ſhall within one Month after his Year is expired, yield up to the INhabitants of the Pariſh, Town or Hamlett at ſome publick meeting appointed by the inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants a perfect Account of all Moneys he hath received and paid within the Year by reaſon of his ſaid Office, and of whom;
<pb n="132" facs="tcp:109137:73"/>what ſumm to whom he hath paid the ſame, what Moneys are in Arrear for Fines, Forfeitures, Penalties, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and if any over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plus be in his hands, he ſhall render the ſame to the next Surveyor for the uſe of the Pariſh, Town or Hamlett, to be disburſed in and about the Highwayes the year fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing. And if the Surveyor ſhall not make ſuch an Account and payment, then two Juſtices near the Pariſh upon complaint may examine the buſineſs upon Oath, and upon default found in the Surveyor they may com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit him to the Gaol of the County, City, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> there to remain until he have made a true Account and payment.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> All Juſtices of Aſſize, Oyer and Terminer, and Juſtices of peace are im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>powred to hear and determine all matters concerning charitable Gifts for the amending and ekeping in repair any common HIgh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes, Pavements, Streets, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> within their Commiſſion; and to make Orders for the due employment of ſuch Gifts, (except the Gift be made to the uſe of any Colledge, Hall, Free-School or Hoſpital, who have proper Viſitors of thier own) and to deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine all offences and defects in Surveyors concerning the ſame; and in eaſe any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon be aggrieved by ſuch Order, he may
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:109137:73"/>Appeal to the Court of Chancery as in caſe of a Decree made upon the Statute of <hi>Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritable uſes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. idem.</hi> No travelling Wayn, Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gon, Cart or Carriage, wherein any Goods, Burthens or Wares ſhall be carried or drawn for hire, (other than ſuch Carts and Carriages as are employed about Husbandry and ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>naging of Lands, and in carrying of Hay, Straw, Corn unthreſhed, Coal, Chalk, Tim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber for ſhipping, materials for Building, Stones of all ſorts, or ſuch Ammunition or Artillery as ſhall be for His Majeſties ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice) ſhall at any one time travle, be drawn or go in any publick or common Highway with above ſeven Beaſts, whereof ſix ſhall draw in pairs; nor with above eight Oxen, or ſix Oxen and two Horſes: nor ſhall at any time carry above 2000. weight between the Firſt of <hi>October</hi> and the Firſt of <hi>May,</hi> (except ſuch paticulars as aboveſaid) nor above 3000. weight between the Firſt of <hi>May</hi> and the Firſt of <hi>October;</hi> nor above five Quarters of Wheat, Meal, Meſline, Rye, Peaſe, Beans, Tares; nor above eight Quarters of Barley, Mault or Oats; nor ſhall any Wagon, Wayn or Carriage be em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed for the ſaid uſes, the Wheels whereof are leſs in breadth than four Inches in the
<pb n="134" facs="tcp:109137:74"/>Tyre, upon pain every owner of ſuch Wagon, Wayn or Carriage, Horſe, Beaſts or Oxen, ſhall for every of the ſaid offences forfeit 40. Shillings, to be divided into three equal parts; one to the <hi>Surveyors of the High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes</hi> where any of the offences ſhall be committed, towards the repairing of the highwayes of the Pariſh there; the other part to the <hi>Overſeers of the Poor</hi> of the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh where the offence is committed, for the relief of the poor there; and one other part to him that ſhall diſcover and proſecute for the ſaid offences.</p>
               <p>Theſe Penalties are to be levied by diſtreſs of all or any the Horſes, Beaſts or Oxen, and to be diſtributed as aforeſaid by the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, Surveyors of the Highwayes, and Overſeers of the Poor of the pariſh where the offence is committed; and in caſe the Penalties be not payd within three dayes after diſtreſs, then the ſame to be ſold, ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dring the overplus, the charges of keeping and ſelling firſt deducted.</p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="statutes">
                  <body>
                     <head>Statutes for repairing particular Highwayes, <hi>viz.</hi>
                     </head>
                     <p>Stat. 39 <hi>El.</hi> ch. 19. For repairing the High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes in the Wild of <hi>Suſſex, Surrey</hi> &amp; <hi>Kent.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <pb n="135" facs="tcp:109137:74"/>
                     <p> Stat. 37 <hi>H.</hi> 8. chap. 3. For <hi>Huntington</hi>-Lane near to <hi>Cheſter.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Stat. 14 <hi>H.</hi> 8. ch. 6. <hi>&amp;</hi> 26 <hi>H.</hi> 8. ch. 7. For laying out new Highwayes in the Wild of <hi>Kent</hi> and <hi>Suſſex.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Stat. 1 <hi>M.</hi> par. 2. ch. 5. For the Cawſey between <hi>Dorchester</hi> and <hi>Sherborn.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Stat. 18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 10. For the Kings Ferry in <hi>Kent.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="statutes">
                  <body>
                     <head>Statutes for particular Bridges.</head>
                     <p>Stat. 18 <hi>H.</hi> 6. chap. 28. For making of <hi>Burford</hi> and <hi>Culhamford</hi> Bridge.</p>
                     <p>Stat. 18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 17. <hi>&amp;</hi> 27 <hi>H.</hi> 7. ch. 25. For the maintenance of <hi>Rocheſter</hi> Bridge.</p>
                     <p>Stat. 18 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 20. For the repair of the Bridges within a mile of <hi>Oxford.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Stat. 23 <hi>Eliz.</hi> chap. 11. For the mainte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance of the Bridges over <hi>Toffe</hi> in <hi>Wales.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Stat. 39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> chap. 23. For making and repairing of <hi>Newport</hi> and <hi>Carleon</hi> Bridges over the River <hi>Uſek.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Stat. 39 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 24. For building and maintenance of a Bridge at <hi>Wilton</hi> upon <hi>Wye,</hi> near <hi>Roſs</hi> in <hi>Herefordſhire.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Stat. 3. <hi>Jac.</hi> chap. 23. For making and repairing <hi>Chepſtow</hi> Bridge.</p>
                     <p>Stat. 14 <hi>Car.</hi> 2. ch. 6. For building and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pairing <hi>Laycock</hi> and <hi>Rey</hi> Bridges in <hi>Wilt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhire,</hi>
                        <pb n="136" facs="tcp:109137:75"/>and <hi>Stratford</hi> Bridge in <hi>Middleſex.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <p>By the ſame Act it is provided, That all Bridges ſhall have ſufficient Walls or Poſts, and Rails on each ſide thereof, four Foot high at the leaſt; adn that the ſame be from time to time ſufficiently kept and repaired.</p>
               <p>Paſch. 10 <hi>E.</hi> 3.28, 29. <hi>Coke</hi> 2 Part of the <hi>Inſtitutes,</hi> fol. 701. Bridges are to be repaired by the whole County by common. Right, if it be not known who ought to do the ſame otherwiſe.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Rolls</hi> Caſes, 1. part, f. 368. If a man erect a Mill for his own particular profit, and cut a new Courſe for the Water to come to it, and makes a new Bridge over the ſame, and the Kings ſubjects uſe to ride over the ſame as over a common Bridge, ſuch Bridge ought to be repaired by him who hath the Mill, and not by the County; becauſe he erected it for his own profit.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Coke</hi> 2. part <hi>Inſtit.</hi> ſo. 700. If man which holdeth an 100 Acres of Land ought to repair a Bridge by tenure of the ſame, do alien 20 Acres thereof to one man, and 10. Acres to another man; in ſuch caſe every owner or occupier of ſuch Lands muſt be charged proportionably for their ſaid Lands.</p>
               <p>22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. chap. 5. <hi>Coke</hi> 2. part <hi>Inſtit.</hi> fo. 702, <hi>Dalt.</hi> J.P. chap. 13. fo. 41. If any.
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:109137:75"/>Bridge be wholly in a City or other Town-Corporate, the inhabitants of the ſame City or Town Corporate muſt repair it: And where ſuch Bridge lyes out of ſuch City or Corporate-Town, the ſame muſt be made by the inhabitants of the Shire or Riding within which the ſame Shire ſhall be. And if part of a Bridge be in one Shire or Riding, City or Corporate-Town, and one part in another, then every of them ſhall be charged to make and repair ſuch part as ſhall lye and be within their own limits.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Crompt.</hi> 186. b. 43. Aſſ. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 13. fo. 42. Such as are chargeable to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pair a Bridge may enter upon any other mans land or ſoyl adjoyning, and lay their Stone, Lime, Timber or other things neceſſary there for the repairing and amending thereof, and the owner of the Lands ſhall have no Action therefore; for it is for the common profit. And the party that is chargeable to repair a Bridge, muſt alſo maintain the way at each end thereof, (although the ſoyl be to another;) and if the ends be broken by the Water-courſe, he muſt follow the Water<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe and mend the way.</p>
               <p>Stat. 22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. ch. 5. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 13. fo. 4. Where a common Bridge in the Kings HIghway is in decay, and that it cannot
<pb n="138" facs="tcp:109137:76"/>be proved or known, who, nor what Lands are chargeable to the repairing thereof, four Juſtices of the peace (one of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) within the Shire or Riding wherein ſuch de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cayed Bridges be; and if they be in a City or Town-corporate, then four ſuch Juſtices of peace there may within the limits of their ſeveral Commiſſions call before them the Conſtables, or two of the moſt honeſt Inhabitants of every Town and Pariſh with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the Shire, Riding, City or Town-corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate wherein ſuch Bridge or any parcel there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of ſhall happen to be; and the Juſtices (upon the appearance of the Conſtables or other inhabitants, and with their aſſents) may tax every inhabitant in any ſuch City, Town or Pariſh within their limits, to ſuch reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able ſumm of Money as by their diſcretions they ſhall think convenient, as well for the repairing of ſuch Bridge as alſo for the making and repairing of the Highwayes, by the ſpace of 300. Foot next adjoyning to the ends of any ſuch Bridge.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Coke</hi> 2. part Inſtit. fo. 704. This Taxation ought not to be made by the Juſtices without the conſent of the Conſtables or inhabitants, nor by them without the Juſtices; and this Tax ought to be upon every inhabitant in particular, and not to be ſet upon the Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred,
<pb n="139" facs="tcp:109137:76"/>Pariſh, Town, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for then one or few might be diſtrained upon the whole.</p>
               <p>Stat. 22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. ch. 5. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 13. fo. 40. <hi>Coke</hi> 2. part Inſtit. fol. 701, 702. Where a Franchiſe, City or Borough is a County of it ſelf, and hath not four or more Juſtices of the peace, (whereof one or more are of the <hi>Quorum</hi>) in this caſe no other Juſtices of the peace of any Shire or County have any power to meddle there by this Act; but ſuch decay muſt be amended by the Common Law, by ſuch remedies as they were antiently before the Statute of 22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. <hi>ſupra.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Coke</hi> 2. part Inſtit. fo. 704. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J. P. ch. 18. fo. 40. The Juſtices of peace af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Taxation is made, ſhall cauſe the names and ſumms of every particular perſon ſo Taxed, to be written in a Roll indented in Parchment, for every Hundred, and ſealed with their Seals.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Coke</hi> part <hi>idem,</hi> fo. 705. <hi>Dalt.</hi> J.P. ch. <hi>&amp;</hi> fol. <hi>idem.</hi> 22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. ch. 5. The Juſtices may make two Collectors of every Hundred to gather the Money ſo taxed; which ſaid Collectors having received one part of the Roll thereof indented, have power to gather all the Money therein mentioned; and if refuſal be made upon demand, then to
<pb n="140" facs="tcp:109137:77"/>diſtrain and ſell ſuch diſtreſs, rendring the overplus to the owner, if any be.</p>
               <p>Stat. 22 <hi>H.</hi> 8. ch. <hi>idem. Dalt.</hi> ch. <hi>&amp;</hi> fo. <hi>ead.</hi> The Juſtices are likewiſe to appoint two Surveyors, who (from time to time as often as need ſhall require) ſhall ſee ſuch decayed Bridges and Wayes repaired and amended, to whoſe hands the Collectors muſt pay the money by them received.</p>
               <p>Stat. <hi>idem.</hi> Dalt. <hi>idem.</hi> The Collectors and Surveyors, and their Executors and Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtrators and every of them ſhall from time to time make a true Account to the ſaid Juſtices of peace, of the Receipts, Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments and Expences of the ſaid ſumms of Money; and if any of them refuſe ſo to do, then the ſaid Juſtices of peace from time to time at their diſcretions may make out Proceſs againſt the ſaid Collectors and Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyors, their Executors and Adminiſtrators by Attachment, Precept or Warrant under their hands and ſeals, returnable at their general Seſſions of the Peace; and the ſaid Juſtices may allow ſuch reaſonable Coſts and charges to the ſaid Surveyors and Collectors upon their account, as to them ſhall ſeem meet.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="13" type="chapter">
               <pb n="141" facs="tcp:109137:77"/>
               <head>
                  <hi>CHAP. XIII.</hi> The Office of the Diſtributors of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſion for the deſtruction of noyſom Fowl and Vermin.</head>
               <p>STat. 8 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 15. <hi>&amp;</hi> 14 <hi>Eliz.</hi> ch. 11. In every Pariſh the Churchwardens with ſix other pariſhioners (to be required by the Churchwardens) ſhall yearly in one of the Holydays in <hi>Eaſter-week,</hi> and at every other time when it ſhall be needful, tax and aſſeſs every perſon having the poſſeſſion of any Lands or Tythes within that Pariſh, to pay ſuch ſumms of money as they ſhall think meet, according to the quantity of ſuch their Lands or Tythes; and if any perſon do deny to pay the ſame, or do not pay the ſame with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in fourteen dayes after requeſt made by the Churchwardens or one of them, then ſuch perſon ſhall forfeit for every time Five ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings; which (together with the ſumm aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſed) ſhall be levied by diſtreſs of the goods and chattels of ſuch perſon, to be taken by the Churchwardens or one of them; the ſame diſtreſs to be ordered and uſed as diſtreſſes taken for Amerciaments in any
<pb n="142" facs="tcp:109137:78"/>Leet. And as well the ſaid ſumms as pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>palties (if any of them be ſo levied) ſhall be yearly by the ſaid Churchwardens or one of them for the time being, delivered by Bills indented to two honeſt and ſubſtantial per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons of the ſaid Pariſh, which ſhall be elected and appointed by the Churchwardens, and ſhall be named, <hi>The Diſtributors of the Proviſion for the deſtruction of noyſom Fowl and Vermin.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And if the ſaid Churchwardens, ſix per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons or Diſtributors, or any of them ſhall refuſe or make default in the execution of any part of this Act, contrary to the form thereof, then ſuch offendor ſhall forfeit for every default Five pounds; the one moiety to the King, the other to him or them (uſing Tillage yearly within the ſame Shire) that will ſue for the ſame in any Court of Record.</p>
               <div type="rewards">
                  <head>The Reward of thoſe who deſtroy the ſaid noyſom Fowl and Vermin, <hi>viz.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>Theſe <hi>Diſtributors</hi> being ſo choſen, and having money, ſhall give and pay of the ſame money ſo to them delivered to every perſon that ſhall bring to them any Heads of <hi>old Crows, Pyes,</hi> or <hi>Rooks</hi> taken within the ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Pariſhes, for the Heads of every three of them, One penny.</p>
                  <pb n="143" facs="tcp:109137:78"/>
                  <p> For the heads of every ſix <hi>young Crows, Choughs, Pyes,</hi> or <hi>Rooks,</hi> One penny.</p>
                  <p>For every ſix Eggs of any of them, One penny.</p>
                  <p>For every 12. Stares heads, One penny.</p>
                  <p>For every head of Merton, Hawks, Furſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kite, Mold-kite, Buzzard, Schagge, Cormo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant, or Ringtayl, Two pence.</p>
                  <p>And for every two Eggs of them, One penny.</p>
                  <p>For every Iron or Oſprayes head, Four pence.</p>
                  <p>For the head of every Woodwal, Pye, Jay, Raven or Kite, One penny.</p>
                  <p>For the head of every bird called the Kings-fiſher, One penny.</p>
                  <p>For the head of every Bulfinch or other bird that devoureth the Bud of Fruit-trees, One penny.</p>
                  <p>For the head of every Fox or Grey, Twelve pence.</p>
                  <p>For the head of every Fitchew, Polcat, Weaſel, Stoat, Fair, Badge or Wildcat, One penny.</p>
                  <p>For the head of every Otter or Hedgehog, Two pence.</p>
                  <p>For the heads of every three Rats, or twelve Mice, One penny.</p>
                  <pb n="144" facs="tcp:109137:79"/>
                  <p> For the heads of every Moldwarp or Want, an Half penny.</p>
                  <p>For the heads of every which Birds and Vermin the ſaid <hi>Diſtributors</hi> ſhall give and pay to the bringer of them as before is limi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted.</p>
                  <p>And if upon any Account to be made in the end and determination of the office of any ſuch <hi>Diſtributors,</hi> any money be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maining in their hands, it ſhall be by Bill indented delivered to thoſe that ſhall ſucceed them in the ſaid Office, to be by them diſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buted in manner aforeſaid.</p>
                  <p>This gives no Authority to uſe any Engine for the deſtruction of the before-mentioned Birds or Vermin, which ſhall diſturb or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy the building or breeding of Hawks, Herons, or Swans; or to the hurt of any Doves, or Deer, or Coney-warren; nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſhall any thing be given to any perſon for the Head of any ſuch Vermin or Fowl taken in any Park or Warren, nor for Stares taken in Dove-houſes, nor to the killing or bringing of the Head of any Kite or Raven killed in any City or Town-corporate, or within two Miles of the ſame.</p>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
                  <pb facs="tcp:109137:79"/>
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
